[
  {
    "id": "d769215e-e0c9-4d3f-85a0-ef9535a0a29f",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built the Great Pyramid of Giza?",
    "correctAnswer": "Egyptian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mayan\",\"Roman\",\"Greek\",\"Persian\",\"Mesopotamian\",\"Chinese\",\"Incan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "483c6e05-6a6c-47a7-b365-c04b80294f8f",
    "question": "Who was the first Emperor of Rome?",
    "correctAnswer": "Augustus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Julius Caesar\",\"Nero\",\"Constantine\",\"Caligula\",\"Claudius\",\"Hadrian\",\"Marcus Aurelius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1296b13c-88e2-425e-a925-9b51615b851e",
    "question": "Which ancient wonder was located in Alexandria?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lighthouse",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hanging Gardens\",\"Colossus\",\"Great Pyramid\",\"Temple of Artemis\",\"Mausoleum\",\"Zeus Statue\",\"Parthenon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "20b71850-7587-4d81-b5ea-20446ceeb3b8",
    "question": "What ancient civilization developed hieroglyphics?",
    "correctAnswer": "Egyptian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Babylonian\",\"Sumerian\",\"Chinese\",\"Aztec\",\"Incan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dfac2f7a-62f7-4784-80e1-eed964c16ef0",
    "question": "Which Greek city-state defeated the Persian army at Marathon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Athens",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sparta\",\"Corinth\",\"Thebes\",\"Macedonia\",\"Troy\",\"Rhodes\",\"Delphi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "badd9f2f-3ab3-477d-844d-e91fdcd97dc8",
    "question": "What material did ancient Egyptians use to write on?",
    "correctAnswer": "Papyrus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Paper\",\"Parchment\",\"Vellum\",\"Animal skins\",\"Clay tablets\",\"Bamboo\",\"Silk\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0826dfc9-ea54-4722-b325-c33c228b8fa5",
    "question": "Who was the legendary founder of Rome?",
    "correctAnswer": "Romulus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Caesar\",\"Augustus\",\"Brutus\",\"Remus\",\"Aeneas\",\"Cicero\",\"Nero\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e2cfa8db-7060-40d6-bf72-8f0cf45da9e1",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built Machu Picchu?",
    "correctAnswer": "Incan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aztec\",\"Mayan\",\"Egyptian\",\"Roman\",\"Greek\",\"Chinese\",\"Persian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "06244de9-fe93-4e58-b418-81c13db533df",
    "question": "Who was the famous queen of ancient Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cleopatra",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nefertiti\",\"Hatshepsut\",\"Nefertari\",\"Isis\",\"Tiye\",\"Ankhesenamun\",\"Meritaten\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d896132-256f-4d4b-ad33-1fe77f1348d8",
    "question": "What ancient structure in England consists of standing stones?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stonehenge",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hadrian's Wall\",\"Tower of London\",\"Roman Baths\",\"Tintagel Castle\",\"Silbury Hill\",\"Avebury\",\"Skara Brae\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f2daa02-470c-45ec-a40b-5130b0bce1c0",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization created the calendar we base ours on?",
    "correctAnswer": "Roman",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Egyptian\",\"Babylonian\",\"Chinese\",\"Mayan\",\"Persian\",\"Sumerian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "29453dd4-a70d-496a-9b65-c3fd561ef8ec",
    "question": "What was the main language of ancient Rome?",
    "correctAnswer": "Latin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Italian\",\"Etruscan\",\"Germanic\",\"Aramaic\",\"Hebrew\",\"Punic\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b3577977-56ea-493b-b67c-b6e7fcf3a6fd",
    "question": "Which river was central to ancient Egyptian civilization?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nile",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tigris\",\"Euphrates\",\"Amazon\",\"Ganges\",\"Indus\",\"Yellow\",\"Danube\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0177e1db-f9d9-48c9-9b4b-1bf32f8b6618",
    "question": "Who was the famous Macedonian king who conquered Persia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexander the Great",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Philip II\",\"Leonidas\",\"Ptolemy\",\"Perseus\",\"Antigonus\",\"Seleucus\",\"Cassander\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c865ce3c-1bcb-424b-bcb1-3c28330d30c4",
    "question": "What ancient city was destroyed by Mount Vesuvius?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pompeii",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Athens\",\"Rome\",\"Alexandria\",\"Carthage\",\"Byzantium\",\"Troy\",\"Ephesus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "509ffd12-2e2d-499b-b070-95d3f2b74aea",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization first used coined money?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lydian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Egyptian\",\"Roman\",\"Babylonian\",\"Persian\",\"Chinese\",\"Phonecian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0818090b-28ba-40f9-9ab3-dd508f507a6c",
    "question": "What was the name of the legendary Trojan War hero?",
    "correctAnswer": "Achilles",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Perseus\",\"Theseus\",\"Jason\",\"Odysseus\",\"Hercules\",\"Ajax\",\"Hector\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d98c9c3-c18f-4433-94fc-9256424532d9",
    "question": "Who is considered the father of modern medicine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hippocrates",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Galen\",\"Aristotle\",\"Plato\",\"Socrates\",\"Archimedes\",\"Pythagoras\",\"Democritus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ee21529-6583-4626-b64b-ace6114fb8c3",
    "question": "What did Romans call their public square or marketplace?",
    "correctAnswer": "Forum",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Agora\",\"Colosseum\",\"Pantheon\",\"Atrium\",\"Plaza\",\"Circus\",\"Basilica\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce2412e1-a45d-4889-900c-bb8c7537ff0b",
    "question": "Which Chinese dynasty built most of the Great Wall?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ming",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Han\",\"Tang\",\"Qin\",\"Zhou\",\"Song\",\"Yuan\",\"Sui\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "834a052c-51dc-4a5c-abe7-067b1cf450ce",
    "question": "Who wrote The Iliad and The Odyssey?",
    "correctAnswer": "Homer",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sophocles\",\"Aristotle\",\"Plato\",\"Euripides\",\"Herodotus\",\"Virgil\",\"Socrates\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d516048-0e2b-4360-812c-327c2e15f618",
    "question": "What ancient structure was built as a tomb for an emperor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Taj Mahal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Colosseum\",\"Parthenon\",\"Stonehenge\",\"Acropolis\",\"Great Pyramid\",\"Pantheon\",\"Hagia Sophia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5582ddbc-775d-46b0-98f9-93992f1ac053",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is credited with inventing paper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Chinese",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Roman\",\"Greek\",\"Persian\",\"Mesopotamian\",\"Indian\",\"Mayan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "53583d8f-bcf1-46bd-a487-5b41a39b7c27",
    "question": "Who was the Roman goddess of love?",
    "correctAnswer": "Venus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Diana\",\"Minerva\",\"Juno\",\"Vesta\",\"Ceres\",\"Flora\",\"Fortuna\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c8afd55-d148-426e-8137-39ae71d67f72",
    "question": "What was the main crop of ancient Mayan civilization?",
    "correctAnswer": "Maize",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Wheat\",\"Rice\",\"Potatoes\",\"Cotton\",\"Quinoa\",\"Beans\",\"Squash\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1aeec399-afc3-4690-96a7-7d7ee9e96170",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built Petra in Jordan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nabataeans",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Romans\",\"Egyptians\",\"Greeks\",\"Persians\",\"Babylonians\",\"Hittites\",\"Phoenicians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d1bfe38d-58b3-4209-a6aa-330b3b88d9d4",
    "question": "Which Greek god was the king of gods?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zeus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Apollo\",\"Poseidon\",\"Ares\",\"Hades\",\"Hermes\",\"Dionysus\",\"Hephaestus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f78c5a0d-bd21-408a-a027-2b567d848f20",
    "question": "What ancient civilization built the city of Carthage?",
    "correctAnswer": "Phoenicians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greeks\",\"Romans\",\"Egyptians\",\"Persians\",\"Babylonians\",\"Etruscans\",\"Berbers\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "23d1829e-c4d9-43ef-9887-561d1e5b2fa8",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization used cuneiform writing?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mesopotamian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Chinese\",\"Mayan\",\"Incan\",\"Indus Valley\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c1e6077-5574-46d9-8c44-485cf35f04e2",
    "question": "What was the main economic activity in ancient Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Agriculture",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mining\",\"Trade\",\"Fishing\",\"Manufacturing\",\"Banking\",\"Construction\",\"Warfare\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e891ac12-ad40-4316-83a1-13f752e8b504",
    "question": "What civilization is known for Step Pyramids?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mayan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Babylonian\",\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Chinese\",\"Persian\",\"Incan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "75b377b8-f349-4ada-99cd-c669c14f8776",
    "question": "What ancient trading route connected East and West?",
    "correctAnswer": "Silk Road",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Spice Route\",\"Amber Road\",\"Incense Route\",\"Gold Route\",\"Tea Horse Road\",\"Salt Route\",\"Tin Route\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "862edffc-b28d-475d-9082-ce44b088c91f",
    "question": "Which ancient city was said to have hanging gardens?",
    "correctAnswer": "Babylon",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Athens\",\"Rome\",\"Alexandria\",\"Persepolis\",\"Memphis\",\"Thebes\",\"Carthage\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce907c5b-4a19-4bfa-89e7-2eee7a6de168",
    "question": "What was ancient Rome's main legislative body?",
    "correctAnswer": "Senate",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Forum\",\"Assembly\",\"Consilium\",\"Curia\",\"Parliament\",\"Council\",\"Congress\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "71fbfd3c-38a0-4de8-bca5-e6677fcf50bd",
    "question": "What famous ancient library was in Alexandria?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Library",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Imperial Library\",\"Royal Archive\",\"Museum\",\"Academy\",\"Repository\",\"Athenaeum\",\"Bibliotheca\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ffb2383-319d-40f1-8686-befc613adcc5",
    "question": "Which ancient culture built step pyramids called ziggurats?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mesopotamian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Mayan\",\"Aztec\",\"Greek\",\"Chinese\",\"Incan\",\"Indian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2759bdb8-7b61-48bf-aaaa-7cbd44b30d09",
    "question": "What type of government did ancient Athens have?",
    "correctAnswer": "Democracy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Monarchy\",\"Oligarchy\",\"Theocracy\",\"Republic\",\"Empire\",\"Dictatorship\",\"Aristocracy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "18ac13e6-23f7-4266-bc08-5cfc58da5bb3",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is famous for terracotta warriors?",
    "correctAnswer": "Chinese",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Japanese\",\"Egyptian\",\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Persian\",\"Indian\",\"Mayan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9cf12b12-7639-488e-97fb-8fba5120d57f",
    "question": "What ancient Greek city-state was known for its military?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sparta",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Athens\",\"Corinth\",\"Thebes\",\"Troy\",\"Argos\",\"Delphi\",\"Rhodes\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcea5fa8-bc32-41cb-9e7c-ed9bee425190",
    "question": "What was the primary building material in ancient Mesopotamia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mud brick",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Stone\",\"Wood\",\"Marble\",\"Concrete\",\"Granite\",\"Limestone\",\"Adobe\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6f53a61-8796-400a-a5cd-d5983b1db1c6",
    "question": "Which civilization first domesticated horses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Eurasian Steppe peoples",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Chinese\",\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Mayan\",\"Persian\",\"Mesopotamian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "632bee78-e26c-4109-9e50-a502b62e8469",
    "question": "What ancient city is now Istanbul?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Athens\",\"Rome\",\"Alexandria\",\"Troy\",\"Carthage\",\"Babylon\",\"Persepolis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1197d5f9-266e-469b-a91e-7ab7331a4915",
    "question": "Who was the Egyptian sun god?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ra",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Osiris\",\"Horus\",\"Anubis\",\"Thoth\",\"Set\",\"Ptah\",\"Amun\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "572576a5-745e-460a-831f-47cff84179e1",
    "question": "What was the famous ancient Greek temple to Athena?",
    "correctAnswer": "Parthenon",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Acropolis\",\"Pantheon\",\"Temple of Zeus\",\"Delphi\",\"Erechtheion\",\"Temple of Apollo\",\"Temple of Artemis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ec82237-6284-4d5b-912f-5388b43a23e5",
    "question": "Which ancient empire was ruled by Ashoka?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mauryan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gupta\",\"Kushan\",\"Chola\",\"Mughal\",\"Satavahana\",\"Vijayanagara\",\"Maratha\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "51734121-44f6-4e27-9b9e-4c5556a972d4",
    "question": "What was the main religion in ancient Rome before Christianity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Polytheistic paganism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Judaism\",\"Mithraism\",\"Zoroastrianism\",\"Islam\",\"Hinduism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Taoism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a79ba8e-af17-410e-980a-57f21d818cdd",
    "question": "What is the world's oldest known religious building?",
    "correctAnswer": "Göbekli Tepe",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Stonehenge\",\"Pyramids\",\"Ziggurat of Ur\",\"Newgrange\",\"Malta temples\",\"Caral\",\"Jericho Tower\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a96ee9a-a3fa-47da-bbe2-70bb39253522",
    "question": "Which famous ancient battle was fought at Thermopylae?",
    "correctAnswer": "Greeks vs Persians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Romans vs Carthaginians\",\"Greeks vs Romans\",\"Egyptians vs Hittites\",\"Spartans vs Athenians\",\"Romans vs Gauls\",\"Macedonians vs Persians\",\"Greeks vs Trojans\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d96f4cd-68d9-4c6d-a860-8d04cff93a21",
    "question": "What was the name of ancient Egypt's writing system?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hieroglyphics",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cuneiform\",\"Phoenician\",\"Demotic\",\"Linear A\",\"Sanskrit\",\"Oracle Bone Script\",\"Proto-Sinaitic\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9446a535-c054-45e5-83c8-a741150110a0",
    "question": "What animal was sacred in ancient Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cat",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Dog\",\"Cow\",\"Crocodile\",\"Eagle\",\"Snake\",\"Monkey\",\"Lion\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4842ecb9-5948-4f40-890d-61e978f099b8",
    "question": "Which civilization first developed the concept of zero?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mayan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Indian\",\"Arabic\",\"Chinese\",\"Greek\",\"Roman\",\"Babylonian\",\"Egyptian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f146b949-abb8-4a89-bef2-1c4d1a461b6d",
    "question": "What were ancient Roman soldiers called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Legionaries",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hoplites\",\"Knights\",\"Centurions\",\"Gladiators\",\"Praetorians\",\"Cavaliers\",\"Guardsmen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "942d31db-fe73-4137-a5f4-af5032f9cc2f",
    "question": "What were Ancient Greek storytellers called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bards",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Scribes\",\"Poets\",\"Scholars\",\"Sophists\",\"Rhetors\",\"Sages\",\"Troubadours\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8d25303-5825-4b30-a06a-0fab30c6a0da",
    "question": "Which ancient people first domesticated corn?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mesoamericans",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"North Americans\",\"Chinese\",\"Egyptians\",\"Indians\",\"Africans\",\"Europeans\",\"South Americans\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a963456-8396-4859-ba0f-9152869b36de",
    "question": "What was the ancient Mayan writing system called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Glyphs",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cuneiform\",\"Hieroglyphics\",\"Runes\",\"Pictographs\",\"Ideograms\",\"Script\",\"Codex\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd853d7b-5fa5-42d7-879c-d144560eb5ef",
    "question": "What was the main language of ancient Greece?",
    "correctAnswer": "Greek",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Latin\",\"Aramaic\",\"Hebrew\",\"Phoenician\",\"Etruscan\",\"Coptic\",\"Persian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:25:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b932c1a-6a18-41a1-b877-a62585c5fc11",
    "question": "Which ancient ruler established the first Persian Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyrus the Great",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Darius I\",\"Xerxes\",\"Cambyses II\",\"Artaxerxes\",\"Nebuchadnezzar\",\"Hammurabi\",\"Sargon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ae9506f-21ad-4134-af90-01f28c54c68f",
    "question": "What was the ancient Roman term for a public bath?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thermae",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Atrium\",\"Forum\",\"Basilica\",\"Colosseum\",\"Domus\",\"Insulae\",\"Aqueduct\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "438206e5-9e69-4f69-94f2-3b79657306f1",
    "question": "Which ancient people first used the arch in architecture?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mesopotamians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greeks\",\"Egyptians\",\"Romans\",\"Chinese\",\"Mayans\",\"Incas\",\"Phoenicians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fbb57f51-70d7-4e17-b7f1-233f9fec8fdf",
    "question": "What was the name of the ancient Egyptian afterlife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Duat",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Elysium\",\"Valhalla\",\"Hades\",\"Aaru\",\"Sheol\",\"Xibalba\",\"Tartarus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0dfa622d-5c42-4ee0-a0c8-9968a8c3969f",
    "question": "What was the primary weapon of a Greek hoplite?",
    "correctAnswer": "Spear",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sword\",\"Bow\",\"Sling\",\"Dagger\",\"Axe\",\"Javelin\",\"Club\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "da923284-3216-4fbd-83ed-dafe4c523011",
    "question": "What significant event occurred in Rome in 64 CE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Fire",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fall of the Republic\",\"Caesar's assassination\",\"Vesuvius eruption\",\"Barbarian invasion\",\"Civil war\",\"Plague outbreak\",\"Senate dissolution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9487b376-b10c-47bb-b078-793bdc3bb9e0",
    "question": "Which island was home to the ancient Minoan civilization?",
    "correctAnswer": "Crete",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sicily\",\"Cyprus\",\"Rhodes\",\"Sardinia\",\"Malta\",\"Corsica\",\"Lesbos\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d696c46b-65e0-4451-b749-86f835d89155",
    "question": "What was the main export of ancient Phoenicia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Purple dye",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Olive oil\",\"Wine\",\"Grain\",\"Gold\",\"Marble\",\"Cedar wood\",\"Silk\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "24968411-bd85-413e-9cc8-4f3e18566206",
    "question": "Which ancient emperor built a wall in Britain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hadrian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Augustus\",\"Constantine\",\"Trajan\",\"Marcus Aurelius\",\"Claudius\",\"Nero\",\"Antoninus Pius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "696e6e7d-e0e8-401b-b9ac-63e70ba8a33e",
    "question": "What ancient civilization invented concrete?",
    "correctAnswer": "Roman",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Egyptian\",\"Persian\",\"Chinese\",\"Mesopotamian\",\"Mayan\",\"Indian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "18c398c7-fa0a-4b3a-a07c-2707f2e6262f",
    "question": "What was the official language of the Byzantine Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Greek",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Latin\",\"Aramaic\",\"Coptic\",\"Slavic\",\"Persian\",\"Arabic\",\"Turkish\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a48a19d-fca1-474a-9f5d-98aeaf174a7f",
    "question": "Which battle ended the Western Roman Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Ravenna",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Adrianople\",\"Battle of Chalons\",\"Battle of Milvian Bridge\",\"Battle of Actium\",\"Battle of Alesia\",\"Battle of Cannae\",\"Battle of Zama\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f500ac2-1c7d-43d3-8ccb-c7ff6b81f9fe",
    "question": "What was the ancient Athenian assembly called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ecclesia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Boule\",\"Areopagus\",\"Agora\",\"Pnyx\",\"Demos\",\"Senate\",\"Acropolis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "621f8ce6-0f79-408e-9ed6-66d3f9c52a76",
    "question": "What was the first Chinese imperial dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Qin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Han\",\"Zhou\",\"Tang\",\"Song\",\"Ming\",\"Yuan\",\"Shang\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "60ad2a75-44f2-4d29-9412-3b2d6d0fac0d",
    "question": "Who was the last Ptolemaic ruler of Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cleopatra VII",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ptolemy XV\",\"Ptolemy XIV\",\"Ptolemy XIII\",\"Ptolemy XII\",\"Ptolemy XI\",\"Arsinoe IV\",\"Berenice IV\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "891ae3d1-70c7-4cff-904d-55be9e03fdb2",
    "question": "What was the main Mesopotamian religious structure?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ziggurat",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Temple\",\"Pyramid\",\"Shrine\",\"Cathedral\",\"Monastery\",\"Pagoda\",\"Stupa\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "90779325-044b-4d18-864d-5733c860994b",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built the city of Persepolis?",
    "correctAnswer": "Persian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Egyptian\",\"Roman\",\"Babylonian\",\"Assyrian\",\"Phoenician\",\"Hittite\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "824eb7b9-b5c8-4ff9-b949-a7ada2745e8b",
    "question": "What material was the world's first writing on?",
    "correctAnswer": "Clay",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Papyrus\",\"Stone\",\"Wood\",\"Bone\",\"Silk\",\"Metal\",\"Leather\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "73e22797-5672-44bb-af16-619bf6dda8c0",
    "question": "What religious system did Emperor Constantine embrace?",
    "correctAnswer": "Christianity",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mithraism\",\"Sol Invictus\",\"Jupiter worship\",\"Isis cult\",\"Zoroastrianism\",\"Judaism\",\"Manichaeism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3432a9f5-6b9d-4f08-89e0-b749f8ba46a0",
    "question": "What was ancient China's administrative examination?",
    "correctAnswer": "Imperial Examination",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mandarin Test\",\"Scholar Selection\",\"Confucian Trial\",\"Civil Service Test\",\"Bureaucratic Exam\",\"Literary Assessment\",\"Academic Challenge\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8e03448-d1e2-4175-afa1-011fa8757fc9",
    "question": "In what year did Rome become a republic?",
    "correctAnswer": "509 BCE",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"753 BCE\",\"44 BCE\",\"27 BCE\",\"476 CE\",\"410 CE\",\"323 BCE\",\"146 BCE\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "afde211c-8604-4ddc-a4a3-9e712a9803e6",
    "question": "What was the prominent religion in ancient Persia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zoroastrianism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mithraism\",\"Judaism\",\"Hinduism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Jainism\",\"Manichaeism\",\"Paganism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e90232ae-a67f-4666-acf5-430dba182031",
    "question": "What was the ancient Greek marketplace called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Agora",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Forum\",\"Acropolis\",\"Parthenon\",\"Stoa\",\"Gymnasium\",\"Academy\",\"Palaestra\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a766360-2abf-4831-ad68-fccdb20bf40a",
    "question": "Which civilization used the quipu for record-keeping?",
    "correctAnswer": "Incan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mayan\",\"Aztec\",\"Egyptian\",\"Chinese\",\"Mesopotamian\",\"Indian\",\"Greek\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "844ec318-5649-44ec-9daf-34c6ed43361b",
    "question": "What ancient ruler created one of the first legal codes?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hammurabi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cyrus\",\"Solomon\",\"Sargon\",\"Ramses\",\"Ashoka\",\"Nebuchadnezzar\",\"Darius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "509d13d7-e324-4937-b4de-fb0175b7fca3",
    "question": "What Chinese philosophy emphasizes harmony and order?",
    "correctAnswer": "Confucianism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Taoism\",\"Legalism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Mohism\",\"Naturalism\",\"Logicians\",\"School of Names\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "af6533a3-f1ac-4542-9c40-f731fd2a1922",
    "question": "What was the capital of the Hittite Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hattusa",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Babylon\",\"Nineveh\",\"Ur\",\"Susa\",\"Persepolis\",\"Tarsus\",\"Ashur\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "84c025ed-148d-464a-ac0d-0122eabe80d5",
    "question": "What ancient civilization first used iron weapons?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hittite",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Babylonian\",\"Chinese\",\"Greek\",\"Assyrian\",\"Persian\",\"Phoenician\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "24a94a57-058d-47b9-a0c9-1b0cd74e1b04",
    "question": "What was the ancient Roman unit of currency?",
    "correctAnswer": "Denarius",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aureus\",\"Sestertius\",\"As\",\"Solidus\",\"Dupondius\",\"Quadrans\",\"Follis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "158951a5-a9ae-41bb-b587-299fff8e69ed",
    "question": "Which ancient Indian emperor embraced Buddhism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ashoka",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Chandragupta\",\"Kanishka\",\"Harsha\",\"Samudragupta\",\"Bindusara\",\"Pulakeshin\",\"Rajendra\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b0da979-6211-4913-aa63-dc7218c847ce",
    "question": "What was the highest position in the Roman Republic?",
    "correctAnswer": "Consul",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Senator\",\"Emperor\",\"Tribune\",\"Censor\",\"Praetor\",\"Aedile\",\"Quaestor\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b287d3f-eaaf-4023-8aea-c7013e330ada",
    "question": "What were ancient Greek warships called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Triremes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Galleys\",\"Caravels\",\"Longships\",\"Junks\",\"Biremes\",\"Pentekonters\",\"Quinqueremes\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0a0be43-de24-432a-b4ff-72329b446ebb",
    "question": "Which war featured Athens versus Sparta?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peloponnesian War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Persian Wars\",\"Trojan War\",\"First Punic War\",\"Macedonian Wars\",\"Sacred War\",\"Corinthian War\",\"Social War\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3b48099-5b7e-4ccc-bd4d-f2806eb8fce4",
    "question": "What was the ancient Egyptian term for pharaoh?",
    "correctAnswer": "Per-aa",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nesu-bit\",\"Nemes\",\"Ankh\",\"Hedjet\",\"Uraeus\",\"Ka\",\"Ba\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b20fb12-ea9f-40bb-a8fe-2eedc38888fc",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built Chichen Itza?",
    "correctAnswer": "Maya",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aztec\",\"Olmec\",\"Toltec\",\"Zapotec\",\"Inca\",\"Mixtec\",\"Teotihuacan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ed6a579-8f2a-4ca8-aa6c-877dce65b630",
    "question": "What did Romans call non-citizens?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peregrini",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Plebeians\",\"Slaves\",\"Barbarians\",\"Provincials\",\"Foreigners\",\"Aliens\",\"Outlanders\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "538aa1af-a04f-4b51-9ac1-7d2028fffe8f",
    "question": "What was a Roman gladiator who used a net called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Retiarius",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Murmillo\",\"Thracian\",\"Secutor\",\"Dimachaerus\",\"Hoplomachus\",\"Bestiarius\",\"Provocator\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "72eee1a9-4156-41e2-892f-a347ba021e17",
    "question": "What happened at the Battle of Marathon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Athenians defeated Persians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Romans defeated Greeks\",\"Spartans defeated Athenians\",\"Greeks defeated Trojans\",\"Carthage fell to Rome\",\"Egypt fell to Alexander\",\"Athens fell to Sparta\",\"Macedonians defeated Persians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea3acff4-86b1-4499-88a6-50f74caaa6e5",
    "question": "Which civilization dominated modern-day Turkey?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hittites",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Akkadians\",\"Sumerians\",\"Babylonians\",\"Assyrians\",\"Hurrians\",\"Elamites\",\"Lydians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7512da9d-9ea6-400e-8b3d-1a9b1aa2e4c9",
    "question": "What was the first known alphabet developed by?",
    "correctAnswer": "Phoenicians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptians\",\"Sumerians\",\"Greeks\",\"Hebrews\",\"Akkadians\",\"Persians\",\"Hittites\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "19d5852a-7ced-4d14-be3e-a39884b7adb7",
    "question": "What was the Roman name for Scotland?",
    "correctAnswer": "Caledonia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hibernia\",\"Britannia\",\"Gaul\",\"Lusitania\",\"Germania\",\"Dacia\",\"Thracia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "912dddb9-5bd6-4bd7-88c4-f926edd375e4",
    "question": "What was the main social class in ancient Sparta?",
    "correctAnswer": "Spartiate",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Helot\",\"Perioikoi\",\"Plebeian\",\"Patrician\",\"Citizen\",\"Nobility\",\"Demoi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a3b32157-b107-4f9f-8322-3def87698de5",
    "question": "What was the currency of ancient Athens?",
    "correctAnswer": "Drachma",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Obol\",\"Stater\",\"Talent\",\"Mina\",\"Tetradrachm\",\"Shekel\",\"Daric\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ce1ab70-6948-4538-b97d-a0d18996b716",
    "question": "Who wrote the first known history book?",
    "correctAnswer": "Herodotus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thucydides\",\"Xenophon\",\"Livy\",\"Tacitus\",\"Plutarch\",\"Suetonius\",\"Josephus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ebe787b1-760d-4b72-ab48-2a3ea2ec97fc",
    "question": "What was ancient Rome's state religion before Christianity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Roman polytheism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mithraism\",\"Cult of Isis\",\"Sol Invictus\",\"Judaism\",\"Zoroastrianism\",\"Greco-Roman paganism\",\"Imperial cult\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b11fe8d-565a-4d17-b30f-7d8da05178e3",
    "question": "What ended the Bronze Age around 1200 BCE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bronze Age Collapse",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Trojan War\",\"Volcanic eruption\",\"Great Flood\",\"Sea People invasion\",\"Climate change\",\"Iron invention\",\"Disease outbreak\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "070b2c44-0e3d-45a0-b213-728629dbfab6",
    "question": "What was the ancient Babylonian hanging structure?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hanging Gardens",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Etemenanki Ziggurat\",\"Ishtar Gate\",\"Processional Way\",\"Esagila Temple\",\"Palace of Nebuchadnezzar\",\"Walls of Babylon\",\"Academy of Sciences\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9f3359f-8c71-4ec7-bb66-120a73d14ffc",
    "question": "What were ancient Egyptian tombs called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mastabas",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pyramids\",\"Sepulchers\",\"Catacombs\",\"Necropolises\",\"Sarcophagi\",\"Mausoleums\",\"Vaults\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0657c63f-16e3-4bf9-ba5b-87b554a88074",
    "question": "What was ancient Rome's road network called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Via Romana",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cursus Publicus\",\"Iter Romanum\",\"Via Appia\",\"Strata Romana\",\"Via Publica\",\"Iter Imperialis\",\"Roman Highway\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b9b6a89-0f6f-4158-b800-e114c06f814e",
    "question": "What was the ancient Greek concept of natural law?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nomos",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Logos\",\"Ethos\",\"Pathos\",\"Polis\",\"Arete\",\"Physis\",\"Eudaimonia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "19ee9b8f-dde2-4cbb-8f32-e80c97fb2477",
    "question": "What was the largest Roman amphitheater?",
    "correctAnswer": "Colosseum",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Circus Maximus\",\"Verona Arena\",\"Pula Arena\",\"El Djem\",\"Theater of Pompey\",\"Flavian Amphitheater\",\"Capua Amphitheater\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e210da42-3866-4ec2-b4ab-d26262a357c5",
    "question": "What civilization built the Lion Gate at Mycenae?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mycenaean",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Minoan\",\"Dorian\",\"Ionian\",\"Athenian\",\"Spartan\",\"Trojan\",\"Thessalian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1a9fe4d-0def-46e9-9ba4-7ee8cd9eb7b5",
    "question": "What was the main crop of ancient Mesopotamia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Barley",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Wheat\",\"Millet\",\"Rice\",\"Maize\",\"Oats\",\"Sorghum\",\"Rye\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8bbbdbbd-4b1e-4969-8471-eb0a53d4ce99",
    "question": "Which empire did Chandragupta Maurya found?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mauryan Empire",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gupta Empire\",\"Kushan Empire\",\"Chola Empire\",\"Maratha Empire\",\"Vijayanagara Empire\",\"Satavahana Empire\",\"Pallava Empire\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5bbb4862-163d-4bd8-93fd-180a87c3e613",
    "question": "What was the Spartan educational system called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Agoge",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gymnasium\",\"Academy\",\"Lyceum\",\"Paideia\",\"Ephebeia\",\"Didaskaleion\",\"Schola\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T00:48:22.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb3776a3-f367-492b-9431-acc6221bc604",
    "question": "Which Carthaginian general lost his eye crossing the Alps?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hannibal Barca",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hasdrubal\",\"Hamilcar\",\"Hanno\",\"Mago\",\"Gisco\",\"Adherbal\",\"Maharbal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "beadeed2-3334-4c83-bbbd-1143f6360603",
    "question": "What was the ancient Greek term for foreigner?",
    "correctAnswer": "Barbaros",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Xenos\",\"Metoikos\",\"Perioikoi\",\"Doulos\",\"Helot\",\"Douloi\",\"Paroikos\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "28eddefd-c99e-4581-99b0-5ac1325d87a9",
    "question": "Which ancient culture constructed the Ajanta Caves?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vakataka",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Maurya\",\"Gupta\",\"Chola\",\"Kushan\",\"Pallava\",\"Chalukya\",\"Satavahana\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f378c43-4532-4ab5-afc8-77381f2a5a5e",
    "question": "Where was the ancient port city of Carthage located?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tunisia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Italy\",\"Greece\",\"Turkey\",\"Egypt\",\"Lebanon\",\"Morocco\",\"Spain\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "916dc8c9-1ba9-49b3-b43c-b70a3db3e674",
    "question": "What was the site of Xerxes' defeat in 480 BCE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Salamis",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marathon\",\"Thermopylae\",\"Plataea\",\"Artemisium\",\"Mycale\",\"Eurymedon\",\"Aegospotami\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c92356eb-2e5b-444c-ad49-18ee7e6390d2",
    "question": "Which Chinese philosophical work was written by Laozi?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tao Te Ching",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"I Ching\",\"Analects\",\"Art of War\",\"Book of Changes\",\"Mencius\",\"Daodejing\",\"Zhuangzi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9054641f-0f3c-4af7-bcda-fd0fd5362eff",
    "question": "What was the ancient Assyrian capital?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nineveh",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ashur\",\"Babylon\",\"Nimrud\",\"Dur-Sharrukin\",\"Hatra\",\"Arbela\",\"Calah\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea6efdb0-d39f-434f-81d0-a2022bede113",
    "question": "Which pharaoh moved Egypt's capital to Amarna?",
    "correctAnswer": "Akhenaten",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tutankhamun\",\"Ramesses II\",\"Thutmose III\",\"Hatshepsut\",\"Amenhotep III\",\"Seti I\",\"Khufu\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7727680-1872-410e-bba0-f6ac9f230caa",
    "question": "Which battle ended the Third Punic War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Carthage",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Zama\",\"Battle of Cannae\",\"Battle of Thapsus\",\"Battle of Bagradas\",\"Battle of Utica\",\"Battle of Tunis\",\"Battle of Mago\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "af1e3bb8-7a07-41e3-b7f7-e6fa612c14c7",
    "question": "Who was the famous female Pharaoh of the 18th Dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hatshepsut",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nefertiti\",\"Cleopatra\",\"Tiye\",\"Nefertari\",\"Ankhesenamun\",\"Meritaten\",\"Twosret\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb41ab45-938a-42ea-9046-1e3635ce249c",
    "question": "What was the name of Alexander's horse?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bucephalus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pegasus\",\"Incitatus\",\"Chiron\",\"Hippomenes\",\"Arion\",\"Balius\",\"Xanthus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c06f1b59-90fd-44c8-9ae0-942373ee6db5",
    "question": "Which Athenian leader reformed democracy in 508 BCE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cleisthenes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Solon\",\"Pericles\",\"Draco\",\"Themistocles\",\"Ephialtes\",\"Cimon\",\"Aristides\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "98f52a5f-ceca-4d1c-b14a-7c7a79d52f5b",
    "question": "What civilization lived in Mohenjo-daro?",
    "correctAnswer": "Indus Valley",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mesopotamian\",\"Vedic\",\"Dravidian\",\"Mauryan\",\"Gupta\",\"Harappan\",\"Egyptian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "da2c1f2f-01ec-4819-9a9a-0affa31337fa",
    "question": "Which Roman emperor was known as Princeps Civitatis?",
    "correctAnswer": "Augustus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tiberius\",\"Claudius\",\"Nero\",\"Caligula\",\"Trajan\",\"Hadrian\",\"Marcus Aurelius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff20f058-a89a-4d36-949c-244b91502955",
    "question": "What was the ancient Mesopotamian writing material?",
    "correctAnswer": "Clay tablets",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Papyrus\",\"Parchment\",\"Vellum\",\"Bamboo slips\",\"Palm leaves\",\"Stone tablets\",\"Wax tablets\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8730223d-333b-4094-b5ae-907c01a6de8f",
    "question": "Who succeeded Ramesses II as pharaoh?",
    "correctAnswer": "Merneptah",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Seti II\",\"Amenhotep\",\"Tutankhamun\",\"Thutmose\",\"Akhenaten\",\"Horemheb\",\"Seti I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "82e49f3f-665b-4c5c-8137-b59adb2bfcdf",
    "question": "What ancient structure was discovered by Schliemann?",
    "correctAnswer": "Troy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mycenae\",\"Knossos\",\"Tiryns\",\"Pylos\",\"Thebes\",\"Athens\",\"Sparta\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c84bc317-c853-4a42-bc70-b70b4be278d0",
    "question": "Which Chinese dynasty introduced civil service exams?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sui",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Han\",\"Tang\",\"Song\",\"Ming\",\"Yuan\",\"Zhou\",\"Qin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d87fea0-ddb0-45db-86b9-b73612a93977",
    "question": "What was Augustus' name before becoming emperor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Octavian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Octavius\",\"Gaius\",\"Julius\",\"Caesar\",\"Marcus\",\"Agrippa\",\"Germanicus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "06d41d7f-deea-4e6b-a476-9f99398ab9ce",
    "question": "Which ancient historian wrote Histories of the Persian Wars?",
    "correctAnswer": "Herodotus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thucydides\",\"Xenophon\",\"Plutarch\",\"Tacitus\",\"Livy\",\"Polybius\",\"Suetonius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "57a8fcae-dfa9-4fee-8ab4-58518138b3bc",
    "question": "What sacred text forms the basis of Zoroastrianism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Avesta",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vedas\",\"Torah\",\"Talmud\",\"Quran\",\"Tripitaka\",\"Upanishads\",\"Sutras\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "40aef634-c2ae-404c-8b64-8517ec7d62a6",
    "question": "Which people created the world's first star catalog?",
    "correctAnswer": "Babylonians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptians\",\"Chinese\",\"Greeks\",\"Mayans\",\"Indians\",\"Persians\",\"Sumerians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c0ce6b99-aea3-4160-878a-25892adf17d6",
    "question": "What was the ancient Greek city-state alliance called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Delian League",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Peloponnesian League\",\"Achaean League\",\"Aetolian League\",\"Amphictyonic League\",\"Hellenic League\",\"Ionian League\",\"Boeotian League\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ea77060-4f08-4164-aebe-1e8fab223448",
    "question": "Which Roman general sacked Corinth in 146 BCE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lucius Mummius",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Scipio Aemilianus\",\"Titus Flamininus\",\"Aemilius Paullus\",\"Cato the Elder\",\"Marius\",\"Sulla\",\"Pompey\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e5c5e98-a7fa-41ed-8f03-cd2d1563f8e0",
    "question": "What civilization created the first astronomical calendar?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sumerian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egyptian\",\"Babylonian\",\"Greek\",\"Chinese\",\"Mayan\",\"Aztec\",\"Indian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8301984-f963-401d-906f-05a03b8c71e6",
    "question": "Which Roman orator opposed Mark Antony?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cicero",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cato\",\"Brutus\",\"Cassius\",\"Caesar\",\"Pompey\",\"Crassus\",\"Seneca\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b99e4988-dc5f-4491-bcaa-0bc7dd2d7703",
    "question": "What was the Spartan ruling council called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gerousia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ecclesia\",\"Boule\",\"Apella\",\"Ephorate\",\"Senate\",\"Areopagus\",\"Assembly\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "860f0844-6d1c-4c2b-9a27-fb84cda76c69",
    "question": "Which Han dynasty emperor established Confucianism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wu",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gaozu\",\"Wen\",\"Jing\",\"Xuan\",\"Yuan\",\"Cheng\",\"Ai\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5bfc29c4-d400-4168-b2a9-d7ba12b63b2f",
    "question": "Who wrote the ancient Egyptian Book of the Dead?",
    "correctAnswer": "Many scribes over centuries",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Imhotep\",\"Amenhotep\",\"Ptahhotep\",\"Khaemweset\",\"Manetho\",\"Thoth\",\"Osiris\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6abb1cb-4216-489c-a9cd-f4c620127c34",
    "question": "What year was the Library of Alexandria established?",
    "correctAnswer": "285 BCE",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"323 BCE\",\"197 BCE\",\"48 BCE\",\"30 BCE\",\"250 BCE\",\"305 BCE\",\"273 BCE\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cfeff27e-ea53-4311-b5e0-b6ff58e13fc2",
    "question": "Which battle ended Alexander's Indian campaign?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of the Hydaspes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Gaugamela\",\"Battle of Issus\",\"Battle of Granicus\",\"Battle of Tyre\",\"Battle of Gaza\",\"Battle of Persepolis\",\"Battle of Sogdiana\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b571580-18ed-45f8-b3d3-a2ba4dd89610",
    "question": "What was the ancient Etruscan ruling class called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lucumones",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Patricians\",\"Nobles\",\"Aristocrats\",\"Optimates\",\"Oligarchs\",\"Equites\",\"Magistrates\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c2d5cd6-600a-43aa-b3dd-4ef9a1b3265c",
    "question": "Who established the first law code in ancient Athens?",
    "correctAnswer": "Draco",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Solon\",\"Cleisthenes\",\"Pericles\",\"Themistocles\",\"Cimon\",\"Ephialtes\",\"Aristides\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb2c71a6-3f93-41dd-8a3d-bcf75669de20",
    "question": "Which ancient culture built Göbekli Tepe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pre-Pottery Neolithic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sumerian\",\"Akkadian\",\"Babylonian\",\"Hittite\",\"Assyrian\",\"Minoan\",\"Mycenaean\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "216022f8-32a8-4229-9154-927f0fb90bb7",
    "question": "What was the final battle of the Punic Wars?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Zama",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Cannae\",\"Battle of Trebia\",\"Battle of Trasimene\",\"Battle of Metaurus\",\"Battle of Carthage\",\"Battle of Drepana\",\"Battle of Mylae\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "223a4667-0a83-4ac2-a326-694983c9a564",
    "question": "Which mathematician worked at the Library of Alexandria?",
    "correctAnswer": "Euclid",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pythagoras\",\"Archimedes\",\"Aristotle\",\"Eratosthenes\",\"Aristarchus\",\"Hipparchus\",\"Diophantus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ced75a8e-ca51-43f0-8f47-507874e6a77b",
    "question": "What was the dominant Persian religion before Islam?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zoroastrianism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mithraism\",\"Manichaeism\",\"Judaism\",\"Christianity\",\"Buddhism\",\"Hinduism\",\"Tengriism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "42a76e48-89e2-4978-bed4-4e128df73f15",
    "question": "Which Maya city was known as 'Place of the Ticks'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tikal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Palenque\",\"Chichen Itza\",\"Uxmal\",\"Coba\",\"Yaxchilan\",\"Caracol\",\"Copan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e93c38c-2a9f-4958-96b6-8d5a80d476e8",
    "question": "Who was the last king of Babylon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nabonidus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nebuchadnezzar II\",\"Belshazzar\",\"Cyrus\",\"Nabopolassar\",\"Marduk-apla-iddina II\",\"Shamash-shum-ukin\",\"Evil-Merodach\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "29448758-f9b2-4e63-a602-60798232b1ef",
    "question": "Which ancient site features the Ishtar Gate?",
    "correctAnswer": "Babylon",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nineveh\",\"Persepolis\",\"Ur\",\"Hattusa\",\"Mohenjo-daro\",\"Thebes\",\"Memphis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f74f3fed-a227-48b5-8fcc-db38ddb6b3b1",
    "question": "What was the ancient Greek festival called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Panathenaia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Dionysia\",\"Olympics\",\"Pythian Games\",\"Nemean Games\",\"Isthmian Games\",\"Thesmophoria\",\"Lenaia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1db7117d-e61d-40ad-9e83-bbec5cd70e82",
    "question": "Who deciphered Egyptian hieroglyphics?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jean-François Champollion",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Howard Carter\",\"Thomas Young\",\"Heinrich Schliemann\",\"Flinders Petrie\",\"Auguste Mariette\",\"Karl Lepsius\",\"James Henry Breasted\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "96988eb0-e444-43a3-987f-ccde67625a0d",
    "question": "Which Athenian leader was ostracized in 482 BCE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Aristides",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Themistocles\",\"Cimon\",\"Ephialtes\",\"Pericles\",\"Alcibiades\",\"Nicias\",\"Cleon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "edb86738-0ef4-4fed-9947-3638f0833ff4",
    "question": "What ancient Mesoamerican city had 'Avenue of the Dead'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Teotihuacan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tenochtitlan\",\"Tikal\",\"Monte Alban\",\"Palenque\",\"Chichen Itza\",\"Copan\",\"Calakmul\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "522e57a3-b27b-4faf-8c56-cc961abd3a2f",
    "question": "Which Roman emperor built the Pantheon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hadrian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Augustus\",\"Nero\",\"Trajan\",\"Constantine\",\"Tiberius\",\"Domitian\",\"Marcus Aurelius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0629dd5-fd4b-4ff8-9d5e-781ec9cd4e43",
    "question": "What ancient Chinese state fought the State of Wei?",
    "correctAnswer": "Qi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Chu\",\"Yan\",\"Han\",\"Zhao\",\"Zhou\",\"Jin\",\"Qin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f495dba5-3b0c-4866-b12a-aeed22d05e55",
    "question": "Who wrote 'The Art of War' in ancient China?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sun Tzu",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Confucius\",\"Mencius\",\"Laozi\",\"Han Fei\",\"Xunzi\",\"Mozi\",\"Zhuangzi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "41602eda-e50c-4fb0-8390-3166d4cbee29",
    "question": "What was Emperor Qin Shi Huang's birth name?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ying Zheng",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Liu Bang\",\"Zhao Zheng\",\"Ying Yi\",\"Wu Zetian\",\"Li Yuan\",\"Zhu Yuanzhang\",\"Aisin Gioro\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "426cd18d-5601-4bf1-bdbc-fa743566821d",
    "question": "Which Greek philosopher taught Alexander the Great?",
    "correctAnswer": "Aristotle",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Plato\",\"Socrates\",\"Diogenes\",\"Epicurus\",\"Zeno\",\"Pythagoras\",\"Heraclitus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b1dc95a-8426-4440-bbef-2ce7c6607eb3",
    "question": "Which dynasty ruled Persia from 224 to 651 CE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sassanid",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Achaemenid\",\"Parthian\",\"Seleucid\",\"Arsacid\",\"Samanid\",\"Safavid\",\"Qajar\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ef64505-d288-4e06-862e-e7e0888a0d51",
    "question": "What was the first Roman colony in Britain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Camulodunum",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Londinium\",\"Verulamium\",\"Aquae Sulis\",\"Eboracum\",\"Isca Dumnoniorum\",\"Viroconium\",\"Lindum Colonia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1a1303f-496c-40bd-a758-cdce5f984d7f",
    "question": "Which Indian emperor unified the subcontinent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ashoka",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Chandragupta Maurya\",\"Harsha\",\"Kanishka\",\"Samudragupta\",\"Akbar\",\"Bindusara\",\"Chandragupta II\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9bc87746-3769-4bd0-9aba-1a8f5901bbde",
    "question": "What was the Eastern Roman Empire capital?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Antioch\",\"Alexandria\",\"Athens\",\"Thessalonica\",\"Ephesus\",\"Trebizond\",\"Nicaea\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c44b50a-9f56-4688-96d8-6ed888b78ef4",
    "question": "Who built the Temple of Artemis at Ephesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Croesus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cyrus\",\"Darius\",\"Xerxes\",\"Alexander\",\"Pericles\",\"Hadrian\",\"Justinian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "664f1d09-3ee7-495a-a8c3-08011de48935",
    "question": "What was the first alphabet in the world?",
    "correctAnswer": "Proto-Sinaitic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Phoenician\",\"Ugaritic\",\"Aramaic\",\"Greek\",\"Hebrew\",\"Egyptian Hieratic\",\"Cuneiform\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e4cdc26-0f35-450f-b83b-bb21ba602b95",
    "question": "Which Maya site has the inscription Temple of Inscriptions?",
    "correctAnswer": "Palenque",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tikal\",\"Chichen Itza\",\"Copan\",\"Calakmul\",\"Yaxchilan\",\"Caracol\",\"Uxmal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Ancient History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:21:06.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7195ec48-ad63-4a84-b77f-b85b2eb1bf53",
    "question": "Which event marked the beginning of the Middle Ages?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fall of Western Roman Empire",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Norman Conquest\",\"Charlemagne's coronation\",\"First Crusade\",\"Black Death\",\"Magna Carta\",\"Hundred Years War\",\"Great Schism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "eadfc03b-3a0c-45be-8c12-4a6959eda7b4",
    "question": "What was the Black Death?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bubonic plague",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Great famine\",\"Religious persecution\",\"Civil war\",\"Volcanic winter\",\"Economic collapse\",\"Viking invasion\",\"Climate change\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f6feb60-78b1-48ab-a010-b9260acf6b25",
    "question": "Who was crowned Holy Roman Emperor in 800 CE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charlemagne",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Otto I\",\"Frederick Barbarossa\",\"Louis the Pious\",\"Conrad II\",\"Henry IV\",\"Charles V\",\"Maximilian I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "46ef9c89-88ce-4a9b-bed3-a37e27d92527",
    "question": "What was a medieval knight's code of conduct called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Chivalry",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Feudalism\",\"Nobility\",\"Honor code\",\"Knighthood\",\"Valor code\",\"Allegiance\",\"Vassalage\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f89995e8-a852-4dfb-92c1-a5e5c1e6fdda",
    "question": "What document limited the power of the English king in 1215?",
    "correctAnswer": "Magna Carta",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Domesday Book\",\"Bill of Rights\",\"Common Law\",\"Declaration of Rights\",\"Constitution\",\"Charter of the Forest\",\"Golden Bull\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b84113cb-831d-4b94-8a30-a504e0eb5fd2",
    "question": "Which people were known for raids in the early Middle Ages?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vikings",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Normans\",\"Saxons\",\"Franks\",\"Goths\",\"Huns\",\"Celts\",\"Lombards\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "37fa264d-12cc-45a6-add7-e7b0a65f3220",
    "question": "Who was King of England during the Norman Conquest?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harold Godwinson",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edward the Confessor\",\"William the Conqueror\",\"Alfred the Great\",\"Canute\",\"Ethelred\",\"Edgar\",\"Edmund II\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e652fe28-01e3-4500-9818-71ca0e23aa3e",
    "question": "What year was the Battle of Hastings?",
    "correctAnswer": "1066",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1086\",\"1099\",\"1215\",\"911\",\"955\",\"1000\",\"1189\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f65c035b-02b5-4d4f-9ea1-15e07ea9c914",
    "question": "What was the system of land ownership called in medieval Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Feudalism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Capitalism\",\"Manorialism\",\"Communism\",\"Mercantilism\",\"Serfdom\",\"Tribalism\",\"Democracy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f6cf148-cb69-402c-a5bb-a71507ed84cb",
    "question": "Which medieval queen was known as 'Eleanor of Aquitaine'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Queen of England and France",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Queen of Spain\",\"Holy Roman Empress\",\"Byzantine Empress\",\"Queen of Scotland\",\"Queen of Poland\",\"Duchess of Burgundy\",\"Princess of Kiev\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba0b3b5e-581a-4815-be56-c9091e354e43",
    "question": "What was the main religion in medieval Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Christianity",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Islam\",\"Judaism\",\"Paganism\",\"Zoroastrianism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Druidism\",\"Manichaeism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4612452c-70bb-404b-92da-7427e6cb5b77",
    "question": "What conflict began in 1337 and lasted until 1453?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hundred Years' War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thirty Years' War\",\"Crusades\",\"War of the Roses\",\"Reconquista\",\"Byzantine-Seljuk Wars\",\"Norman Conquest\",\"Great Schism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e94e2450-d697-4c7f-9c19-a62e6f23ebda",
    "question": "Which medieval military expeditions targeted the Holy Land?",
    "correctAnswer": "Crusades",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jihads\",\"Reconquista\",\"Viking raids\",\"Mongol invasions\",\"Holy wars\",\"Pilgrimages\",\"Trade missions\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1609bf00-97bb-4577-b839-1bc420b183ff",
    "question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Rome\",\"Athens\",\"Alexandria\",\"Antioch\",\"Jerusalem\",\"Ravenna\",\"Thessalonica\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ea5be26-4f6a-40e6-8af4-c72699009c13",
    "question": "Who assembled the Round Table knights?",
    "correctAnswer": "King Arthur",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Richard the Lionheart\",\"Charlemagne\",\"Edward III\",\"Henry V\",\"William the Conqueror\",\"El Cid\",\"Roland\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1fa5ef1e-2a90-4547-a418-554a7d2150fb",
    "question": "What iconic medieval weapon was used at Agincourt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Longbow",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Crossbow\",\"Catapult\",\"Trebuchet\",\"Pike\",\"Halberd\",\"Mace\",\"Morning star\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc4cea7d-1b38-40c7-ab28-4fd268aad633",
    "question": "What was a medieval farming estate called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Manor",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Castle\",\"Village\",\"Monastery\",\"Commune\",\"Borough\",\"Hamlet\",\"Parish\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9360794-c082-45c2-930e-c8361338f808",
    "question": "Who led the First Crusade?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pope Urban II",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Richard the Lionheart\",\"Frederick Barbarossa\",\"Saint Louis\",\"Saladin\",\"Philip Augustus\",\"Emperor Alexios\",\"Peter the Hermit\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1183c57a-fd8f-413c-8f99-d96e7ff2ab30",
    "question": "What prestigious university was founded around 1096?",
    "correctAnswer": "Oxford",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cambridge\",\"Paris\",\"Bologna\",\"Salamanca\",\"Padua\",\"Heidelberg\",\"Prague\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "33fe3a53-90c4-4f22-aede-7f15bc5ebb9b",
    "question": "What was a common medieval punishment device?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stocks",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Electric chair\",\"Gas chamber\",\"Lethal injection\",\"Firing squad\",\"Guillotine\",\"Iron maiden\",\"Brazen bull\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c8eb4fb-19e4-495a-b1da-adaa9979377e",
    "question": "What was the centerpiece of a medieval town?",
    "correctAnswer": "Market square",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Palace\",\"Stadium\",\"Shopping mall\",\"Factory\",\"University\",\"Hospital\",\"Theater\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb1083a2-d252-4712-89de-39000039731e",
    "question": "What was the primary building material for castles?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stone",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Concrete\",\"Steel\",\"Plastic\",\"Glass\",\"Aluminum\",\"Titanium\",\"Copper\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "850506e8-63f1-41ab-a4cd-d1a40733bb30",
    "question": "Which nomadic people were led by Genghis Khan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mongols",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Huns\",\"Vikings\",\"Vandals\",\"Goths\",\"Avars\",\"Slavs\",\"Turks\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d7a4d95-2ee3-44bf-91de-54938626afc9",
    "question": "What was the main occupation of medieval peasants?",
    "correctAnswer": "Farming",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mining\",\"Trading\",\"Fishing\",\"Banking\",\"Manufacturing\",\"Tourism\",\"Teaching\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ac7ef6d-afc3-4943-8677-f5921b3203a4",
    "question": "What medieval craft guild made bread?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bakers",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Butchers\",\"Masons\",\"Tanners\",\"Weavers\",\"Carpenters\",\"Blacksmiths\",\"Cobblers\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "72eaebd5-ea4a-4e66-bdc7-883ecfed7a91",
    "question": "Who became king after the Wars of the Roses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henry VII",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Richard III\",\"Edward IV\",\"Henry VI\",\"Henry VIII\",\"Edward V\",\"Henry V\",\"Edward III\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "67f11d41-8b96-4571-9b4b-0e7ddd604295",
    "question": "What fabric was highly prized in medieval Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Silk",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Polyester\",\"Nylon\",\"Rayon\",\"Spandex\",\"Acrylic\",\"Lycra\",\"Gore-Tex\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "08542016-4b80-4775-a774-43057d3ff24f",
    "question": "Who wrote The Canterbury Tales?",
    "correctAnswer": "Geoffrey Chaucer",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"William Shakespeare\",\"John Milton\",\"Thomas Malory\",\"Dante Alighieri\",\"Giovanni Boccaccio\",\"Christine de Pizan\",\"William Langland\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e76fb8b-9403-46f8-b577-89c32296a31a",
    "question": "What prevented bathing in medieval times?",
    "correctAnswer": "Religious beliefs",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Water shortage\",\"Lack of soap\",\"Skin diseases\",\"Legal prohibition\",\"Cold climate\",\"Technological barriers\",\"Royal decree\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4eed4321-3227-46f3-8403-e4e7295ff1dd",
    "question": "Which dynasty ruled England from 1154 to 1485?",
    "correctAnswer": "Plantagenet",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tudor\",\"Stuart\",\"Norman\",\"Windsor\",\"York\",\"Lancaster\",\"Hanover\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7bdd0a24-d7a1-4038-8c2f-6061b7e293fa",
    "question": "What was a medieval foot soldier called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Infantryman",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Knight\",\"Cavalier\",\"Dragoon\",\"Tank\",\"Commando\",\"Marine\",\"Paratrooper\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2da2448-d454-4cdc-a19e-916553075ee4",
    "question": "What crop failure caused the Great Famine of 1315-1317?",
    "correctAnswer": "Grain",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Potatoes\",\"Tomatoes\",\"Corn\",\"Rice\",\"Cassava\",\"Squash\",\"Sweet potatoes\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b220dbd-56d5-4757-b9f1-6d4de6d9d465",
    "question": "What medieval leader was known as 'The Great'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alfred",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"William\",\"Edward\",\"Richard\",\"Henry\",\"John\",\"Thomas\",\"Stephen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "14680f7d-4217-493c-8df6-7eed65007eb4",
    "question": "What disease was known as 'The White Plague'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tuberculosis",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Smallpox\",\"Measles\",\"COVID-19\",\"AIDS\",\"Ebola\",\"Influenza\",\"Malaria\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "45a09fac-bf51-4c9e-8534-ef5eb3884cd5",
    "question": "What was a common medieval musical instrument?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lute",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Piano\",\"Saxophone\",\"Electric guitar\",\"Synthesizer\",\"Accordion\",\"Banjo\",\"Trombone\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "233a6000-f4f4-4bb4-b1f5-48eaf9579782",
    "question": "What was recaptured in the Reconquista?",
    "correctAnswer": "Iberian Peninsula",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Holy Land\",\"Constantinople\",\"Rome\",\"Alexandria\",\"Jerusalem\",\"Antioch\",\"Britain\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cbfe2f00-0dfc-42e4-a75e-50284614d431",
    "question": "What does a medieval herald do?",
    "correctAnswer": "Make proclamations",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bake bread\",\"Treat wounds\",\"Build castles\",\"Farm land\",\"Command armies\",\"Brew beer\",\"Make armor\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "978e007e-162e-4ff4-94cb-05a1a8c0671e",
    "question": "What happened in Europe in 1054?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Schism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Black Death\",\"First Crusade\",\"Magna Carta\",\"Norman Conquest\",\"Fall of Constantinople\",\"Hundred Years War\",\"War of the Roses\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "635f667d-856a-4a43-b081-5a92047dd4b6",
    "question": "Which civilization built Chichen Itza?",
    "correctAnswer": "Maya",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aztec\",\"Inca\",\"Olmec\",\"Toltec\",\"Zapotec\",\"Mixtec\",\"Tarascan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "254a72ee-2148-4226-82e6-9f019c095a42",
    "question": "What was a medieval town's protective barrier?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wall",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Force field\",\"Electric fence\",\"Barbed wire\",\"Laser grid\",\"Mine field\",\"Security cameras\",\"Guard dogs\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6e0edcda-fca9-488f-9f9e-6fc839d1049e",
    "question": "Who founded the Mali Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sundiata Keita",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mansa Musa\",\"Askia Muhammad\",\"Sonni Ali\",\"Idris Alooma\",\"Ewuare the Great\",\"Sunni Baru\",\"Kankan Musa\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "27bc959a-8376-4a8a-b5ab-12b4cd494aa5",
    "question": "What type of government did medieval Venice have?",
    "correctAnswer": "Republic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Absolute monarchy\",\"Democracy\",\"Communist state\",\"Dictatorship\",\"Theocracy\",\"Military junta\",\"Fascist regime\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b763dbc8-4e5f-476e-9f7a-a2bd895a6d88",
    "question": "What was the main battle tactic of medieval knights?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charge",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Air strike\",\"Tank assault\",\"Naval bombardment\",\"Guerrilla warfare\",\"Trench warfare\",\"Nuclear strike\",\"Chemical warfare\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "56c457a4-9cee-4609-8166-dc0d96e0981a",
    "question": "Who was the Byzantine emperor during the First Crusade?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexios I Komnenos",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Constantine XI\",\"Justinian\",\"Basil II\",\"Heraclius\",\"Leo III\",\"Theodosius II\",\"Michael VIII\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5fc0b211-8e5e-48b4-9b01-d6f64bb64dac",
    "question": "What was the main form of medieval entertainment?",
    "correctAnswer": "Festivals",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Television\",\"Video games\",\"Movies\",\"Social media\",\"Radio\",\"Theme parks\",\"Sports stadiums\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4f406e5-9f16-456e-a6bd-7f4c3fe04bc1",
    "question": "Which pope called for the First Crusade?",
    "correctAnswer": "Urban II",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Innocent III\",\"Gregory VII\",\"Clement V\",\"Alexander III\",\"Benedict IX\",\"John XXII\",\"Boniface VIII\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1b2dd83-9f14-4527-b1d3-93c2ea06b6a3",
    "question": "What was a medieval doctor called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Physician",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Surgeon\",\"Anesthesiologist\",\"Radiologist\",\"Psychiatrist\",\"Neurologist\",\"Cardiologist\",\"Pediatrician\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6af07a06-3688-4594-a44f-4c111a74d03d",
    "question": "What year did the Western Roman Empire fall?",
    "correctAnswer": "476 CE",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"410 CE\",\"500 CE\",\"527 CE\",\"565 CE\",\"632 CE\",\"711 CE\",\"800 CE\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b6f48bd-3586-4335-a388-f89efc28bc1a",
    "question": "What was the staple food of the medieval peasant diet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bread",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hamburgers\",\"Pizza\",\"Pasta\",\"Sushi\",\"Tacos\",\"Curry\",\"Hot dogs\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4cc884c3-3c1e-47fa-b395-6ea60a19b76a",
    "question": "What was a medieval court entertainer called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jester",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Comedian\",\"Actor\",\"Dancer\",\"DJ\",\"VJ\",\"MC\",\"Talk show host\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e48f29ae-5600-4d1e-a6da-4642bd7ef2ab",
    "question": "Who was Joan of Arc?",
    "correctAnswer": "French military leader",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"English queen\",\"Spanish princess\",\"Italian saint\",\"German nun\",\"Scottish rebel\",\"Irish poet\",\"Welsh prophetess\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a6449ca2-2a59-458b-9c23-c99ae109bdfe",
    "question": "What medieval weapon fired large stones?",
    "correctAnswer": "Trebuchet",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Machine gun\",\"Tank\",\"Missile launcher\",\"Flame thrower\",\"Grenade\",\"Land mine\",\"Rocket launcher\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a402b443-ec13-4d43-9133-169b4059a893",
    "question": "What religion emerged from the Arabian Peninsula?",
    "correctAnswer": "Islam",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hinduism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Shintoism\",\"Taoism\",\"Confucianism\",\"Sikhism\",\"Jainism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "09046c34-1b5e-43ef-9b67-f6476300be39",
    "question": "Who fought at the Battle of Tours in 732 CE?",
    "correctAnswer": "Franks and Umayyads",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"British and French\",\"Romans and Huns\",\"Greeks and Persians\",\"Russians and Mongols\",\"Spanish and Portuguese\",\"Italians and Germans\",\"Vikings and Saxons\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c61d58f-9bbc-41c1-ab7c-469331f525e3",
    "question": "What trade route connected Europe and Asia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Silk Road",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Highway 66\",\"Panama Canal\",\"Suez Canal\",\"Trans-Siberian Railway\",\"Interstate Highway\",\"Autobahn\",\"Underground Railroad\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b189859c-c27c-4fc3-86e0-bebdc0344b75",
    "question": "What medieval group practiced medicine and copied books?",
    "correctAnswer": "Monks",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Knights\",\"Peasants\",\"Merchants\",\"Nobles\",\"Serfs\",\"Minstrels\",\"Craftsmen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:35:05.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "452f229b-e1c1-4a6a-9d18-2ac6d0701300",
    "question": "Which medieval king was known as 'The Lionheart'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Richard I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Henry II\",\"John\",\"Edward I\",\"Henry V\",\"Henry VIII\",\"Edward III\",\"William I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9edba86a-39ef-49dd-a91d-abd1ceef3dea",
    "question": "What was the name of Charlemagne's dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Carolingian",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Merovingian\",\"Capetian\",\"Habsburg\",\"Hohenstaufen\",\"Valois\",\"Plantagenet\",\"Ottonian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a385123d-653f-4bd3-b008-5a4f5600bc23",
    "question": "In what year did the Fourth Crusade sack Constantinople?",
    "correctAnswer": "1204",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1096\",\"1147\",\"1189\",\"1217\",\"1271\",\"1291\",\"1099\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fe30025-fe44-480e-b680-54708104cb5b",
    "question": "What was Saladin's political title?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sultan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Caliph\",\"Emir\",\"Shah\",\"King\",\"Emperor\",\"Vizier\",\"Imam\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4cdddc6b-fe15-48a7-bed9-17717462161d",
    "question": "Which English king was defeated at Bannockburn?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edward II",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edward I\",\"Edward III\",\"Henry III\",\"Richard II\",\"Henry IV\",\"John\",\"Henry II\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "06b01777-29e3-4081-93aa-52ed6d06ca5c",
    "question": "Who created the Domesday Book?",
    "correctAnswer": "William the Conqueror",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edward the Confessor\",\"Alfred the Great\",\"Henry II\",\"Richard I\",\"King John\",\"Edward I\",\"Canute\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fd111ff7-4a1f-462f-ab8a-3dbcd5deb8f3",
    "question": "Which disease killed one-third of Europe's population?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bubonic plague",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Smallpox\",\"Typhoid\",\"Cholera\",\"Tuberculosis\",\"Leprosy\",\"Dysentery\",\"Influenza\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0105e629-b04a-4496-bf31-3a7fb1e472c6",
    "question": "What city was the center of Byzantine Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Rome\",\"Athens\",\"Jerusalem\",\"Alexandria\",\"Antioch\",\"Ravenna\",\"Thessalonica\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e28205c2-bf93-4a44-ba3e-7c40391a53e8",
    "question": "Who won the Battle of Bosworth Field in 1485?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henry Tudor",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Richard III\",\"Edward IV\",\"Henry VI\",\"Edward V\",\"Henry IV\",\"Henry VII\",\"Edward III\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc8eab2c-3b76-4411-9ecc-dd7b8aa3aa82",
    "question": "Which university was founded first?",
    "correctAnswer": "University of Bologna",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Oxford University\",\"University of Paris\",\"Cambridge University\",\"University of Salamanca\",\"University of Padua\",\"University of Naples\",\"University of Coimbra\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb2d4ba7-e710-4d0f-8b46-a74ca26966cd",
    "question": "Who was the first Holy Roman Emperor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Otto I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charlemagne\",\"Frederick I\",\"Conrad I\",\"Henry IV\",\"Frederick II\",\"Louis IV\",\"Charles IV\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "804144b5-f389-4fb7-ae15-143dfd781836",
    "question": "What agreement ended the Investiture Controversy?",
    "correctAnswer": "Concordat of Worms",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Treaty of Verdun\",\"Diet of Worms\",\"Peace of Augsburg\",\"Edict of Milan\",\"Treaty of Paris\",\"Dictatus Papae\",\"Fourth Lateran Council\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6b57b4d-1413-488a-9e03-636d498a2579",
    "question": "Which medieval conflict lasted from 1337 to 1453?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hundred Years' War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thirty Years' War\",\"War of the Roses\",\"Crusades\",\"Byzantine-Seljuk Wars\",\"Norman Conquest\",\"Reconquista\",\"Great Schism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7588b041-d365-453a-9f63-33d2e8e27ccc",
    "question": "What was the Battle of Agincourt's significance?",
    "correctAnswer": "English longbow victory",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"First use of cannons\",\"End of Hundred Years' War\",\"Death of Henry V\",\"French naval defeat\",\"Peace treaty signed\",\"Start of English Civil War\",\"Joan of Arc's capture\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "118e3c13-77e0-4e6f-adfb-08bd3a5ca23b",
    "question": "What medieval emperor was known as 'Barbarossa'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Frederick I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Conrad III\",\"Otto IV\",\"Henry VI\",\"Frederick II\",\"Charles IV\",\"Sigismund\",\"Maximilian I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "37a5cb49-b9e1-421f-83bf-521c586215af",
    "question": "Which king signed the Magna Carta?",
    "correctAnswer": "King John",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Richard I\",\"Henry III\",\"Edward I\",\"Henry II\",\"William the Conqueror\",\"Edward III\",\"Henry I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "09d01715-4017-4bb4-b91e-e58ba365084c",
    "question": "What was the highest military order in medieval England?",
    "correctAnswer": "Order of the Garter",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Order of the Bath\",\"Order of the Thistle\",\"Order of St. Patrick\",\"Order of Merit\",\"Order of the Star\",\"Order of the Golden Fleece\",\"Order of St. Michael\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb2ac32a-158d-492e-a3fd-68682937a12e",
    "question": "Which Khan conquered the largest land empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Genghis Khan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Kublai Khan\",\"Hulagu Khan\",\"Batu Khan\",\"Ogedei Khan\",\"Chagatai Khan\",\"Mongke Khan\",\"Jochi Khan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4dd37520-d11a-4f82-a4d8-002722d3a6a5",
    "question": "What was the capital of the Frankish Empire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Aachen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Paris\",\"Rome\",\"Frankfurt\",\"Reims\",\"Mainz\",\"Tours\",\"Lyon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7bdb64a-8005-402b-a978-272d8fa2ffdd",
    "question": "Which monastic order was founded by St. Benedict?",
    "correctAnswer": "Benedictine",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Franciscan\",\"Dominican\",\"Cistercian\",\"Carmelite\",\"Augustinian\",\"Jesuit\",\"Carthusian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2569e33-4c2a-4856-8351-ca1fb3b033f4",
    "question": "What was the language of medieval scholarship?",
    "correctAnswer": "Latin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Greek\",\"Hebrew\",\"Arabic\",\"French\",\"German\",\"English\",\"Italian\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "09e7b243-f505-4b7c-af77-27d6723cf585",
    "question": "What major event occurred in 1066?",
    "correctAnswer": "Norman Conquest",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"First Crusade\",\"Black Death\",\"Great Schism\",\"Hundred Years' War\",\"Fourth Crusade\",\"Fall of Jerusalem\",\"Fall of Constantinople\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "031a032e-5927-4bfc-8894-cce9dd725e03",
    "question": "Which Pope excommunicated Martin Luther?",
    "correctAnswer": "Leo X",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Clement VII\",\"Urban VI\",\"Innocent III\",\"Gregory VII\",\"Boniface VIII\",\"John XXII\",\"Alexander VI\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c1236a6-6196-4be9-a247-e5f2b760435f",
    "question": "What was the political system of feudal Japan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Shogunate",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Monarchy\",\"Democracy\",\"Republic\",\"Empire\",\"Oligarchy\",\"Theocracy\",\"Aristocracy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0eeae6b4-3cac-4a00-990d-bd4534248b9e",
    "question": "What king led the Third Crusade?",
    "correctAnswer": "Richard I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Philip II\",\"Frederick I\",\"Louis IX\",\"Edward I\",\"Henry II\",\"John\",\"Conrad III\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce9f1069-7d7d-479c-adff-2fff3c42c569",
    "question": "Which group of Norse settlers founded Normandy?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vikings",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Saxons\",\"Angles\",\"Jutes\",\"Franks\",\"Goths\",\"Vandals\",\"Lombards\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "56243a7b-adac-46ec-9487-2ac76e520efd",
    "question": "What style of architecture had pointed arches?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gothic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Romanesque\",\"Byzantine\",\"Baroque\",\"Renaissance\",\"Neoclassical\",\"Art Nouveau\",\"Modernist\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c1d58ca-ed2c-456c-be4c-e0c6d7b8663c",
    "question": "Which wars were fought between York and Lancaster?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wars of the Roses",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hundred Years' War\",\"Crusades\",\"Barons' Wars\",\"Peasants' Revolt\",\"Anglo-Scottish Wars\",\"Norman Conquest\",\"Viking Invasions\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "855036a2-d2e8-402a-9261-02bebf4a5627",
    "question": "What was the Byzantine Empire's main religious authority?",
    "correctAnswer": "Patriarch",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pope\",\"Emperor\",\"Archbishop\",\"Cardinal\",\"Metropolitan\",\"Bishop\",\"Priest\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6df9e645-9e2c-4965-ab64-87ff71937af1",
    "question": "What was the dominant trade group in Northern Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hanseatic League",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Silk Road\",\"British East India Company\",\"Dutch East India Company\",\"Templars\",\"Venetian Republic\",\"Medici Bank\",\"Fugger Family\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f024514a-949b-4cae-9ca4-ff3a8fd881b6",
    "question": "Who was the first Norman King of England?",
    "correctAnswer": "William I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"William II\",\"Henry I\",\"Stephen\",\"Richard I\",\"John\",\"Henry II\",\"Edward I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "88a9ee51-2ed6-41cf-a290-c3b277187f57",
    "question": "What was the main army unit in medieval Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Knight",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tank\",\"Submarine\",\"Fighter jet\",\"Aircraft carrier\",\"Nuclear submarine\",\"Stealth bomber\",\"Guided missile cruiser\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5361bf26-6ceb-441e-b93e-c62b12f304ea",
    "question": "What style of illumination used gold leaf?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gothic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Art Deco\",\"Impressionist\",\"Cubist\",\"Surrealist\",\"Pop Art\",\"Abstract\",\"Minimalist\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "10699ecb-dc31-48ba-9715-8f0bcf68687f",
    "question": "What year did the Great Schism begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "1054",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1066\",\"1096\",\"1204\",\"1215\",\"1337\",\"1347\",\"1453\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "df90a331-46b3-4f32-afb6-b24d3eb07c77",
    "question": "Which medieval order cared for pilgrims?",
    "correctAnswer": "Knights Hospitaller",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Knights Templar\",\"Teutonic Knights\",\"Livonian Brothers\",\"Order of Santiago\",\"Order of Calatrava\",\"Order of Alcantara\",\"Order of Christ\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0094b69-8486-4e3e-b603-68f9f97ab627",
    "question": "Who was the last Anglo-Saxon king of England?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harold Godwinson",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edward the Confessor\",\"Edgar the Ætheling\",\"Edmund Ironside\",\"Ethelred the Unready\",\"Sweyn Forkbeard\",\"Canute\",\"Harthacnut\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "abbd1ef1-80eb-4e44-8125-75a4f0cc761e",
    "question": "What was the Islamic golden age period?",
    "correctAnswer": "8th-14th centuries",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1st-5th centuries\",\"15th-19th centuries\",\"20th-21st centuries\",\"3rd-6th centuries\",\"16th-18th centuries\",\"2nd-4th centuries\",\"17th-19th centuries\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8c52e68-0cf3-4e1e-8632-71f3e1e6a5e0",
    "question": "What weapon dominated late medieval warfare?",
    "correctAnswer": "Longbow",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tank\",\"Machine gun\",\"Nuclear weapon\",\"Fighter jet\",\"Submarine\",\"Assault rifle\",\"Guided missile\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c066bc54-82e3-4269-a972-daa410f55251",
    "question": "What medieval city was known as Miklagard?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constantinople",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Rome\",\"Jerusalem\",\"Paris\",\"London\",\"Baghdad\",\"Damascus\",\"Cairo\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2f6de6f-faed-4c0b-8e8d-28811f3f64ec",
    "question": "When did the Eastern Roman Empire fall?",
    "correctAnswer": "1453",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"476\",\"1066\",\"1204\",\"1492\",\"1096\",\"1291\",\"1348\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c344d55-7147-43b7-b656-15b21890f301",
    "question": "Which king established the Star Chamber court?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henry VII",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Henry VIII\",\"Richard III\",\"Edward IV\",\"Edward VI\",\"Mary I\",\"Elizabeth I\",\"James I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dabfb2c5-3a9a-4d4b-b8b0-a514e4b1968e",
    "question": "What was the main disease of the Black Death?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bubonic plague",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Smallpox\",\"Influenza\",\"Tuberculosis\",\"Cholera\",\"Typhus\",\"Malaria\",\"Yellow fever\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "453b8ac4-1cba-45b0-9270-85ddd9b5353e",
    "question": "Which clan ruled Japan as shoguns from 1603-1868?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tokugawa",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Minamoto\",\"Taira\",\"Fujiwara\",\"Hojo\",\"Ashikaga\",\"Oda\",\"Toyotomi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef5a6625-a5f5-415c-92ef-c829a8e4b553",
    "question": "What religion emerged in 7th century Arabia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Islam",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Christianity\",\"Judaism\",\"Hinduism\",\"Buddhism\",\"Zoroastrianism\",\"Sikhism\",\"Jainism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f75224a-d832-4fb6-abe0-a0978e25e4b0",
    "question": "What was a medieval English yeoman?",
    "correctAnswer": "Free land-owning farmer",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Knight\",\"Baron\",\"Duke\",\"Earl\",\"King\",\"Prince\",\"Serf\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "483d5c6e-6a03-4f55-8d03-28dc0a75ae0c",
    "question": "What historical work did Bede write?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ecclesiastical History",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Canterbury Tales\",\"Divine Comedy\",\"Beowulf\",\"Paradise Lost\",\"Decameron\",\"Le Morte d'Arthur\",\"The Prince\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a0de3e1-136b-4dbb-b943-8ea9bfdaea32",
    "question": "Which Abbasid caliph founded the House of Wisdom?",
    "correctAnswer": "Al-Ma'mun",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Harun al-Rashid\",\"Al-Mansur\",\"Al-Mu'tasim\",\"Al-Mutawakkil\",\"Al-Saffah\",\"Al-Mahdi\",\"Al-Mu'tadid\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "822b2f6b-c193-437a-a91a-b16315ae1e02",
    "question": "What medieval legal system used ordeals?",
    "correctAnswer": "Trial by ordeal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jury trial\",\"Civil law\",\"Common law\",\"Constitutional law\",\"Canon law\",\"Martial law\",\"Administrative law\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3aaa638f-7583-431f-9a3b-1ee32880443d",
    "question": "Which religious order was founded by St. Dominic?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dominican Order",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Franciscan Order\",\"Jesuit Order\",\"Benedictine Order\",\"Carmelite Order\",\"Augustinian Order\",\"Cistercian Order\",\"Carthusian Order\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b223e6a2-c66b-4f35-892d-83ecabb31578",
    "question": "What title did Hungarian rulers hold?",
    "correctAnswer": "Magyar király",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tsar\",\"Kaiser\",\"Sultan\",\"Shah\",\"Emperor\",\"Caliph\",\"Maharaja\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2245fb59-0346-4cf8-a0dd-562ee371e986",
    "question": "What famous letter did Luther post in 1517?",
    "correctAnswer": "95 Theses",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Letter of Indulgence\",\"Edict of Worms\",\"Magna Carta\",\"Papal Bull\",\"Confession of Augsburg\",\"Book of Common Prayer\",\"Letter to the Romans\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "163e39b3-21fd-4513-bb39-97f488f417b9",
    "question": "Which Mongol leader conquered China?",
    "correctAnswer": "Kublai Khan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Genghis Khan\",\"Ogedei Khan\",\"Hulagu Khan\",\"Batu Khan\",\"Mongke Khan\",\"Chagatai Khan\",\"Jochi Khan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5717fc1b-1d71-484a-9efa-873d9422fc1b",
    "question": "What was the largest medieval cathedral?",
    "correctAnswer": "Seville Cathedral",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Notre Dame\",\"St. Peter's Basilica\",\"Cologne Cathedral\",\"Canterbury Cathedral\",\"Milan Cathedral\",\"York Minster\",\"Durham Cathedral\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4145b5be-127f-46f5-a8db-8dd184444fd2",
    "question": "Which king created the English Parliament?",
    "correctAnswer": "Simon de Montfort",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edward I\",\"Henry III\",\"John\",\"Henry II\",\"William I\",\"Richard I\",\"Edward III\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2630f20-5658-48ee-960c-d50e916e6130",
    "question": "What was the Ottoman elite infantry called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Janissaries",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Mamluks\",\"Sipahis\",\"Ghazis\",\"Akinjis\",\"Timariots\",\"Dervishes\",\"Bektashis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7866574e-83e1-41fc-ae9f-da08731d2615",
    "question": "What did medieval alchemists seek to create?",
    "correctAnswer": "Philosopher's stone",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Atom bomb\",\"Computer\",\"Internet\",\"Television\",\"Telephone\",\"Radio\",\"Penicillin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:38:50.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "840cd021-492c-4b07-a5e4-c4a8ca859517",
    "question": "Which medieval English archbishop was murdered in 1170?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Becket",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Anselm\",\"Lanfranc\",\"Dunstan\",\"Stephen Langton\",\"Edmund Rich\",\"Simon Sudbury\",\"William Courtenay\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "de4152f9-8125-485d-b077-b0edb987b416",
    "question": "What caused the Great Western Schism of 1378?",
    "correctAnswer": "Multiple pope claimants",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Doctrinal differences\",\"Crusade failures\",\"Eastern church split\",\"Monastic reforms\",\"Investiture dispute\",\"Liturgical changes\",\"Papal taxation\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "13ac6acc-9fd7-4866-b1ff-24d19db5a20d",
    "question": "Who wrote the medieval philosophical work 'Sic et Non'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter Abelard",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Aquinas\",\"Duns Scotus\",\"William of Ockham\",\"Roger Bacon\",\"Albertus Magnus\",\"Anselm\",\"Boethius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d62a860e-0619-4167-8ea0-04b1cbb7c809",
    "question": "Which medieval battle occurred on October 14, 1066?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Hastings",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Stamford Bridge\",\"Battle of Fulford\",\"Battle of Maldon\",\"Battle of Agincourt\",\"Battle of Bosworth\",\"Battle of Falkirk\",\"Battle of Bannockburn\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "525cfac0-ec6c-43e3-a335-cd8f655fc315",
    "question": "What was the Albigensian Crusade targeting?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cathar heresy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Muslim territories\",\"Byzantine Empire\",\"Jewish communities\",\"Viking raiders\",\"Pagan Baltics\",\"Holy Land\",\"Eastern Orthodox\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3bdbb3eb-f853-4653-8526-28b2d6785e04",
    "question": "Which Byzantine emperor introduced iconoclasm?",
    "correctAnswer": "Leo III",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Justinian I\",\"Basil II\",\"Heraclius\",\"Constantine VII\",\"Alexios I\",\"Manuel I\",\"Constantine XI\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "185658d3-bd4b-458f-bbd7-d3a5a3fa318d",
    "question": "What medieval heresy denied Church sacraments?",
    "correctAnswer": "Catharism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Arianism\",\"Nestorianism\",\"Pelagianism\",\"Lollardy\",\"Waldensianism\",\"Bogomilism\",\"Hussitism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3843d58f-900e-4f0d-bfca-56adae09e268",
    "question": "Who led the Golden Horde?",
    "correctAnswer": "Batu Khan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Genghis Khan\",\"Kublai Khan\",\"Hulagu Khan\",\"Ogedei Khan\",\"Chagatai Khan\",\"Mongke Khan\",\"Jochi Khan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9eb9815-50da-4667-800f-22f4aceea457",
    "question": "What was the Treaty of Verdun's significance?",
    "correctAnswer": "Division of Carolingian Empire",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"End of Hundred Years' War\",\"Papal authority limits\",\"Crusader state creation\",\"Islamic-Christian truce\",\"Trade route establishment\",\"Reconquista terms\",\"Baltic pagans' surrender\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "daf1d3f5-8bd4-42e3-b6cb-b1e326c986dd",
    "question": "What was the medieval Islamic legal code called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sharia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hadith\",\"Fiqh\",\"Sunnah\",\"Qiyas\",\"Ijma\",\"Ijtihad\",\"Fatwa\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc2d8487-d9b0-4455-8874-a5d0157cd893",
    "question": "Which order fought in the Northern Crusades?",
    "correctAnswer": "Teutonic Knights",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Knights Hospitaller\",\"Knights Templar\",\"Livonian Brothers\",\"Order of Santiago\",\"Order of Calatrava\",\"Order of Alcantara\",\"Order of Christ\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6a496c7-3e40-4f86-9580-cf988bceef6c",
    "question": "Who was the Byzantine empress from 797 to 802?",
    "correctAnswer": "Irene of Athens",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Theodora\",\"Zoe\",\"Eudokia Makrembolitissa\",\"Theophano\",\"Sophia\",\"Maria of Alania\",\"Euphrosyne\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1ac34a4-1da4-4087-a7b9-93aa37f1a592",
    "question": "Which English aristocrat led the Peasants' Revolt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wat Tyler",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jack Cade\",\"John Ball\",\"Robert Kett\",\"Lambert Simnel\",\"Perkin Warbeck\",\"Bartholomew Steer\",\"Jack Straw\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a5a10e2-6310-4ecd-b57f-dc884e7b971a",
    "question": "What medieval tribe established the Khazar Khaganate?",
    "correctAnswer": "Turkic Khazars",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cumans\",\"Pechenegs\",\"Kipchaks\",\"Bulgars\",\"Avars\",\"Magyars\",\"Oghuz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d2ad464-6fd3-4699-9c43-963ca402dc47",
    "question": "What was the medieval Arabic scientific institution?",
    "correctAnswer": "House of Wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Al-Azhar\",\"Library of Alexandria\",\"Madrasa\",\"Bayt al-Hikma\",\"House of Knowledge\",\"Academy of Sciences\",\"Observatory of Scholars\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0313eaab-b71b-4106-bbb7-8404f35859a9",
    "question": "Which Norse explorer first reached North America?",
    "correctAnswer": "Leif Erikson",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Erik the Red\",\"Harald Hardrada\",\"Cnut the Great\",\"Ragnar Lodbrok\",\"Rollo\",\"Sweyn Forkbeard\",\"Olaf Tryggvason\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bbe3e189-23da-42e8-8487-b074e20dd28f",
    "question": "What medieval Chinese dynasty succeeded the Tang?",
    "correctAnswer": "Song",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Yuan\",\"Ming\",\"Jin\",\"Liao\",\"Western Xia\",\"Sui\",\"Zhou\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "811d5d1d-19bd-46de-9704-124f8ce30082",
    "question": "Which battle ended Moorish rule in Spain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Granada",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa\",\"Battle of Covadonga\",\"Battle of Alarcos\",\"Battle of Guadalete\",\"Battle of Sagrajas\",\"Battle of Uclés\",\"Battle of Simancas\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "feaa9b4a-052f-4ffb-aa47-c60733dee2c4",
    "question": "What medieval text was written by Al-Khwarizmi?",
    "correctAnswer": "Algebra",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Canon of Medicine\",\"Book of Optics\",\"Book of Fixed Stars\",\"Book of Healing\",\"The Incoherence\",\"History of Prophets\",\"Perfect Book\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bff4d6ff-cdc6-4907-918a-c8d2ea3358a0",
    "question": "Which medieval Pope called the First Crusade?",
    "correctAnswer": "Urban II",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gregory VII\",\"Innocent III\",\"Alexander III\",\"Paschal II\",\"Eugenius III\",\"Clement III\",\"Honorius III\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b2e90985-6e77-471d-a184-9dc0b08ed75e",
    "question": "What group established the Kingdom of Northumbria?",
    "correctAnswer": "Angles",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Saxons\",\"Jutes\",\"Vikings\",\"Picts\",\"Scots\",\"Britons\",\"Normans\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8291a33c-7206-4e74-bf50-2625683a0d53",
    "question": "Which Japanese clan fought in the Genpei War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Taira",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tokugawa\",\"Oda\",\"Toyotomi\",\"Hojo\",\"Shimazu\",\"Date\",\"Mori\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d184805e-43cd-442c-86a7-1fbaa37b1ffc",
    "question": "What architectural style preceded Gothic?",
    "correctAnswer": "Romanesque",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Byzantine\",\"Baroque\",\"Renaissance\",\"Neoclassical\",\"Art Nouveau\",\"Tudor\",\"Modernist\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "456f0728-91e4-4bdd-af57-e7b9870716c1",
    "question": "Who was the first Tudor monarch?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henry VII",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Henry VIII\",\"Edward VI\",\"Mary I\",\"Elizabeth I\",\"Richard III\",\"Edward IV\",\"Edward V\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dfdc8968-5438-4800-a1cb-3367e337500e",
    "question": "What did the Fourth Lateran Council establish?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mandatory confession",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Papal election rules\",\"First Crusade\",\"Inquisition\",\"Knights Templar\",\"Church taxation\",\"Clerical celibacy\",\"Excommunication procedures\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e52dc5ea-0797-4eeb-8467-193349d4ed52",
    "question": "Which Chinese invention spread to Europe via Arabs?",
    "correctAnswer": "Paper",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gunpowder\",\"Printing press\",\"Compass\",\"Porcelain\",\"Silk\",\"Tea\",\"Abacus\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b81da486-a78c-40a8-95f0-f586ff7b4505",
    "question": "What was the Carolingian Renaissance?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cultural revival",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Military campaign\",\"Religious reformation\",\"Architectural style\",\"Legal system\",\"Economic policy\",\"Political ideology\",\"Trade network\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1375a9e-d28a-4d0b-9f32-4fee5fcef633",
    "question": "What was the medieval Flemish cloth industry center?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ghent",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bruges\",\"Antwerp\",\"Brussels\",\"Ypres\",\"Lille\",\"Arras\",\"Tournai\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "911e5966-0ac5-484c-bb3e-b698b2c9f79d",
    "question": "Who wrote the medieval 'Book of the City of Ladies'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Christine de Pizan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hildegard of Bingen\",\"Julian of Norwich\",\"Catherine of Siena\",\"Margery Kempe\",\"Marie de France\",\"Heloise d'Argenteuil\",\"Anna Komnene\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5407d773-f694-4a51-a8a9-c12a12ed5d46",
    "question": "What dynasty ruled Mali from 1230 to 1670?",
    "correctAnswer": "Keita",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Songhai\",\"Ghana\",\"Kanem\",\"Bornu\",\"Almoravid\",\"Almohad\",\"Hafsid\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1daed956-939c-4c63-b855-fade584510dc",
    "question": "Who founded the medieval Kingdom of Portugal?",
    "correctAnswer": "Afonso Henriques",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Henry of Burgundy\",\"Sancho I\",\"Ferdinand I\",\"João I\",\"Pedro I\",\"Manuel I\",\"Afonso V\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "489f3ec9-499a-4bd0-969e-deb20d98b68e",
    "question": "What treaty ended the Great Schism in 1417?",
    "correctAnswer": "Council of Constance",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Council of Basel\",\"Council of Ferrara-Florence\",\"Council of Trent\",\"Council of Lyon\",\"Council of Pisa\",\"Council of Vienne\",\"Lateran Council\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "90bf23aa-51dd-46b2-ab2b-fffd506716c4",
    "question": "Which city led the Lombard League against Barbarossa?",
    "correctAnswer": "Milan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Venice\",\"Florence\",\"Genoa\",\"Pisa\",\"Bologna\",\"Naples\",\"Rome\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec704a54-f3e9-446e-ab37-880301e9eda9",
    "question": "What was the Great Heathen Army?",
    "correctAnswer": "Viking force",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Saxon rebels\",\"Celtic warriors\",\"Norman invasion\",\"Crusader battalion\",\"Mongol horde\",\"Moorish fighters\",\"Byzantine troops\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e58c80c3-72f8-4ef6-9621-2119f5c75476",
    "question": "Which Islamic dynasty ruled North Africa and Spain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Umayyad",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Abbasid\",\"Fatimid\",\"Almoravid\",\"Almohad\",\"Ayyubid\",\"Marinid\",\"Zirid\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "21c757aa-6d8a-4130-ab1e-d11a559cb7cf",
    "question": "What was the Bayeux Tapestry depicting?",
    "correctAnswer": "Norman Conquest",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hundred Years' War\",\"Crusades\",\"Black Death\",\"Viking raids\",\"Great Schism\",\"Peasants' Revolt\",\"War of the Roses\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "63a272da-51d8-4476-affc-077be41a2afe",
    "question": "Which Italian city was called the 'Serene Republic'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Venice",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Florence\",\"Milan\",\"Genoa\",\"Pisa\",\"Rome\",\"Naples\",\"Palermo\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "99cbb208-9500-4f3a-99d0-4515fa6e31c9",
    "question": "What was the medieval Persian universal history?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jami al-Tawarikh",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Shahnameh\",\"Tarikh-i Jahangushay\",\"Zafarnama\",\"Baburnama\",\"Akbarnama\",\"Tabaqat-i Nasiri\",\"Tarikh-i Rashidi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fe0aed5-2983-4bb2-9a66-a313418b598f",
    "question": "Which council condemned Jan Hus to death?",
    "correctAnswer": "Council of Constance",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Council of Basel\",\"Council of Florence\",\"Council of Trent\",\"Council of Lyon\",\"Council of Pisa\",\"Council of Vienne\",\"Lateran Council\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c718ad4f-689f-4478-a926-15660175f9e7",
    "question": "Who wrote the medieval work 'Policraticus'?",
    "correctAnswer": "John of Salisbury",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Aquinas\",\"Duns Scotus\",\"William of Ockham\",\"Roger Bacon\",\"Albertus Magnus\",\"Peter Abelard\",\"Boethius\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4acd8f6b-2fe9-49ff-ab8e-5f34faff86a5",
    "question": "Which medieval trade route connected Russia to Baghdad?",
    "correctAnswer": "Volga trade route",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Silk Road\",\"Amber Road\",\"Incense Route\",\"Tea Horse Road\",\"Trans-Saharan Route\",\"Salt Route\",\"Royal Road\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f402817a-ea44-484a-9fe8-7ea4cbb51ab5",
    "question": "What was the Code of Cuenca?",
    "correctAnswer": "Medieval Spanish law",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Byzantine legal code\",\"Islamic religious text\",\"Viking navigation guide\",\"Monastic rule\",\"Feudal obligations\",\"Guild regulations\",\"Merchant handbook\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2047f2ef-a9f9-40d5-b971-bdc37e5cbfcb",
    "question": "Who discovered medieval Arabic numerals?",
    "correctAnswer": "Al-Khwarizmi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ibn Sina\",\"Al-Biruni\",\"Ibn al-Haytham\",\"Al-Farabi\",\"Al-Kindi\",\"Ibn Rushd\",\"Al-Razi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bcbcac53-6869-46ef-8f3b-e446d9c4bea8",
    "question": "What was the medieval Ethiopian royal dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Solomonic",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Zagwe\",\"Axumite\",\"Agaw\",\"Shoan\",\"Gondar\",\"Zimba\",\"Adal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "020b5276-e9ae-484d-8c24-7864353083ee",
    "question": "Which Viking leader besieged Paris in 885?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sigfred",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Rollo\",\"Ragnar Lodbrok\",\"Bjorn Ironside\",\"Harald Bluetooth\",\"Sweyn Forkbeard\",\"Ivar the Boneless\",\"Guthrum\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "11ccd90f-7982-4fff-83a4-55f5be9b9591",
    "question": "What was the Slavic warrior elite called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Druzhina",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Boyars\",\"Voivodes\",\"Knyaz\",\"Bogatyrs\",\"Oprichniki\",\"Streltsy\",\"Huskarls\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee515668-ba3a-4021-b39f-2de955f2c01c",
    "question": "Which dynasty ruled the Delhi Sultanate first?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mamluk",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Khilji\",\"Tughlaq\",\"Sayyid\",\"Lodi\",\"Mughal\",\"Rajput\",\"Maratha\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b82fe9e-391b-4b96-b842-80ef0b39f0bb",
    "question": "Who ruled the Almohad Caliphate after 1147?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abd al-Mu'min",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Yusuf ibn Tashfin\",\"Muhammad an-Nasir\",\"Abu Yaqub Yusuf\",\"Ibn Tumart\",\"Yaqub al-Mansur\",\"Abu Sa'id Uthman\",\"Muhammad al-Mutawakkil\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a1ee40d-870c-4e10-94d5-ba6adf51da42",
    "question": "What was the Burgundian royal residence?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dijon",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Lyon\",\"Chalon\",\"Besançon\",\"Mâcon\",\"Auxerre\",\"Langres\",\"Autun\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "469687d2-5ab2-4e81-aa35-88182016629b",
    "question": "Which emperor founded the Komnenian dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexios I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John II\",\"Manuel I\",\"Andronikos I\",\"Isaac II\",\"Basil II\",\"Constantine X\",\"Michael VII\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8e31d4e1-bd95-435c-88e6-cb6c27202461",
    "question": "What was the Danish Danegeld?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tax to pay Vikings",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Military service\",\"Land measurement\",\"Legal system\",\"Trade regulation\",\"Religious tithe\",\"Marriage dowry\",\"Ship building tax\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f4d7305-1a81-4b85-8d32-23943fdaf9bc",
    "question": "Who translated Aristotle into Arabic?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hunayn ibn Ishaq",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Al-Farabi\",\"Ibn Sina\",\"Al-Kindi\",\"Ibn Rushd\",\"Al-Ghazali\",\"Ibn Khaldun\",\"Al-Razi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "db267989-fe18-4a2d-b903-e4ccc0e49758",
    "question": "What medieval polity was called 'Land of Rus'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Kievan Rus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Muscovy\",\"Novgorod Republic\",\"Golden Horde\",\"Byzantine Empire\",\"Poland-Lithuania\",\"Khazar Khaganate\",\"Bulgarian Empire\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "03506f6b-41f8-4604-9149-6200ddbdbdf6",
    "question": "Which battle ended Anglo-Saxon England?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of Hastings",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Stamford Bridge\",\"Battle of Fulford\",\"Battle of Maldon\",\"Battle of Brunanburh\",\"Battle of Assandun\",\"Battle of Edington\",\"Battle of Tettenhall\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "669d7d8f-0f4c-4b66-9530-86a8ec852557",
    "question": "What was the samurai warrior code?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bushido",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Shinto\",\"Zen\",\"Bakufu\",\"Daimyo\",\"Shogunate\",\"Ronin\",\"Seppuku\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Medieval History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:42:03.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ae974a2-eb5c-4d7d-a3e2-0c271445dffc",
    "question": "In which year did World War I begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "1914",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1916\",\"1918\",\"1912\",\"1920\",\"1910\",\"1922\",\"1908\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5af90ae8-c15c-40e9-a8ce-a512398d7934",
    "question": "Who was the first President of the United States?",
    "correctAnswer": "George Washington",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Jefferson\",\"Abraham Lincoln\",\"John Adams\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"Andrew Jackson\",\"James Madison\",\"Alexander Hamilton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "901c35af-cb0a-443b-838e-76b5391fb129",
    "question": "What happened at Pearl Harbor on December 7, 1941?",
    "correctAnswer": "Japanese attack",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Peace treaty signing\",\"Naval parade\",\"Military exercise\",\"Submarine testing\",\"Aircraft testing\",\"Hurricane damage\",\"Allied invasion\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f66097c1-42a6-43bd-9752-450d250cdc07",
    "question": "Which country was the first to send a person to space?",
    "correctAnswer": "Soviet Union",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"United States\",\"China\",\"Germany\",\"France\",\"Japan\",\"United Kingdom\",\"Canada\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0619932-7bdf-43b9-a8c0-88e45e04e2e5",
    "question": "What was built to separate East and West Berlin?",
    "correctAnswer": "Berlin Wall",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Great Wall\",\"Iron Curtain\",\"Brandenburg Gate\",\"Checkpoint Charlie\",\"Atlantic Wall\",\"Siegfried Line\",\"Maginot Line\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee28efa0-bd4c-4849-a4cf-9bb46b327db0",
    "question": "Who was the leader of Nazi Germany during World War II?",
    "correctAnswer": "Adolf Hitler",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Joseph Stalin\",\"Benito Mussolini\",\"Winston Churchill\",\"Francisco Franco\",\"Heinrich Himmler\",\"Hermann Göring\",\"Joseph Goebbels\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f270af25-1fed-4cb3-b700-71d1ef9e8e7d",
    "question": "In which year did the United States declare independence?",
    "correctAnswer": "1776",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1789\",\"1781\",\"1765\",\"1800\",\"1812\",\"1756\",\"1783\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2f5d5f8-b5fc-4a4f-ab29-92661ed8a08a",
    "question": "What event started the French Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Storming of the Bastille",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Waterloo\",\"Reign of Terror\",\"Tennis Court Oath\",\"Louis XVI execution\",\"Fall of Robespierre\",\"March on Versailles\",\"Napoleon's coronation\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ececfa97-2d0a-4887-a87d-af71a4a98fc5",
    "question": "What was the first country to undergo industrial revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Britain",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"United States\",\"France\",\"Germany\",\"Belgium\",\"Netherlands\",\"Italy\",\"Russia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "47453b3f-196e-4fda-830b-ceea94895272",
    "question": "When did World War II end in Europe?",
    "correctAnswer": "May 8, 1945",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"December 7, 1941\",\"September 1, 1939\",\"June 6, 1944\",\"August 6, 1945\",\"August 15, 1945\",\"July 28, 1914\",\"November 11, 1918\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5708c84c-fb16-435e-b403-737d30a89a75",
    "question": "Which European country had a revolution in 1917?",
    "correctAnswer": "Russia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Germany\",\"France\",\"Italy\",\"Spain\",\"United Kingdom\",\"Poland\",\"Austria\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "41bb3a2a-6f40-45dd-a38c-de2c6251e58f",
    "question": "What was the name of the first atomic bomb dropped?",
    "correctAnswer": "Little Boy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fat Man\",\"Trinity\",\"Big Boy\",\"Destroyer\",\"Peacemaker\",\"Thunderbolt\",\"Devastator\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "32823c52-d277-4984-9f75-45357be8dc54",
    "question": "Which country gifted the Statue of Liberty to the US?",
    "correctAnswer": "France",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"England\",\"Italy\",\"Germany\",\"Spain\",\"Netherlands\",\"Russia\",\"Belgium\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a1c1195-5186-407b-ae23-6939b1725bf6",
    "question": "What year did the American Civil War begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "1861",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1865\",\"1850\",\"1875\",\"1843\",\"1870\",\"1857\",\"1881\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "104c943d-17af-4f3f-976d-22e071a7174a",
    "question": "Who was Britain's Prime Minister during World War II?",
    "correctAnswer": "Winston Churchill",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Neville Chamberlain\",\"Clement Attlee\",\"Anthony Eden\",\"Stanley Baldwin\",\"Harold Macmillan\",\"David Lloyd George\",\"Herbert Asquith\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9df191d1-8668-435b-b364-e969d36e9b7c",
    "question": "What major event began on October 29, 1929?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stock Market Crash",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"World War I\",\"World War II\",\"Korean War\",\"Vietnam War\",\"Great Depression\",\"Cold War\",\"Cuban Missile Crisis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:23.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad3e972f-faaa-461f-80c6-595dd962d044",
    "question": "Who was the first person to walk on the moon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Neil Armstrong",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Buzz Aldrin\",\"Yuri Gagarin\",\"John Glenn\",\"Alan Shepard\",\"Michael Collins\",\"Jim Lovell\",\"Pete Conrad\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "85c33660-6af0-4fb7-b45e-61d83e6fbe7c",
    "question": "What organization was founded after World War II?",
    "correctAnswer": "United Nations",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"League of Nations\",\"European Union\",\"NATO\",\"Warsaw Pact\",\"World Bank\",\"OPEC\",\"NAFTA\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "85164e39-07ff-44bf-a3cc-f35f9bacbb05",
    "question": "Who led India's independence movement?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jawaharlal Nehru\",\"Subhas Chandra Bose\",\"Bhagat Singh\",\"Sardar Patel\",\"B.R. Ambedkar\",\"Muhammad Ali Jinnah\",\"Rabindranath Tagore\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf7a729b-5f75-4fdc-8ba3-93c56a0233f5",
    "question": "What system of government did the USSR have?",
    "correctAnswer": "Communism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Democracy\",\"Monarchy\",\"Fascism\",\"Theocracy\",\"Republic\",\"Dictatorship\",\"Oligarchy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1eafcb12-0354-40c4-9a68-586631120fb2",
    "question": "What event happened on September 11, 2001?",
    "correctAnswer": "Terrorist attacks in the US",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Chernobyl disaster\",\"Hurricane Katrina\",\"Fukushima disaster\",\"Boxing Day tsunami\",\"Haiti earthquake\",\"Berlin Wall fall\",\"Gulf War began\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "72bf771a-18e2-4dce-8c30-3bad1cf23b24",
    "question": "What invention did Alexander Graham Bell patent in 1876?",
    "correctAnswer": "Telephone",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Light bulb\",\"Radio\",\"Television\",\"Automobile\",\"Airplane\",\"Camera\",\"Refrigerator\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5aaf91f2-7181-4507-a858-bc40ccbe06b6",
    "question": "Which war was fought in Vietnam?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vietnam War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Korean War\",\"Gulf War\",\"World War I\",\"World War II\",\"Crimean War\",\"Falklands War\",\"Iraq War\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b80a8878-5398-4866-9206-94af2a7fea7b",
    "question": "Which country was divided into East and West in 1945?",
    "correctAnswer": "Germany",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"France\",\"Italy\",\"Japan\",\"China\",\"Korea\",\"Vietnam\",\"Poland\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b1022ae-b866-45d2-b4a2-0e79812eb838",
    "question": "What period followed the French Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Napoleonic Era",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Industrial Revolution\",\"Renaissance\",\"Reformation\",\"Enlightenment\",\"Colonial Period\",\"Modern Age\",\"Victorian Era\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d9d8e2c-c2b0-499b-898e-6f8b4c740b25",
    "question": "What war ended in 1783 with American independence?",
    "correctAnswer": "American Revolutionary War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"War of 1812\",\"French and Indian War\",\"Civil War\",\"Spanish-American War\",\"Mexican-American War\",\"World War I\",\"Korean War\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ec77660-6b63-4bf3-9e2f-4d6c386ec920",
    "question": "What canal connects the Mediterranean and Red Sea?",
    "correctAnswer": "Suez Canal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Panama Canal\",\"Erie Canal\",\"Kiel Canal\",\"Grand Canal\",\"Corinth Canal\",\"Welland Canal\",\"Gota Canal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "60d48f35-9f5a-4c45-aaa4-cbbe9b2924f5",
    "question": "Who invented the telegraph?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel Morse",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Alexander Bell\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"James Watt\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"Michael Faraday\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "75ac7c51-7c1d-4c89-a15a-891e035f9c24",
    "question": "What form of government ruled France before 1789?",
    "correctAnswer": "Absolute monarchy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Democracy\",\"Republic\",\"Communism\",\"Fascism\",\"Military dictatorship\",\"Theocracy\",\"Constitutional monarchy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a95a5e4-d1b2-44c6-af3a-1721fae9ceb9",
    "question": "What year did the Soviet Union dissolve?",
    "correctAnswer": "1991",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1989\",\"1985\",\"1995\",\"1980\",\"2000\",\"1975\",\"1987\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8421034b-a281-444a-9a83-9332d2568c97",
    "question": "Which president was assassinated in Dallas in 1963?",
    "correctAnswer": "John F. Kennedy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Abraham Lincoln\",\"William McKinley\",\"James Garfield\",\"Richard Nixon\",\"Lyndon Johnson\",\"Franklin Roosevelt\",\"Harry Truman\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "deb7d67a-7daf-4721-91b6-0c4173aef02e",
    "question": "What political movement sought voting rights for women?",
    "correctAnswer": "Suffrage movement",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Civil rights movement\",\"Labor movement\",\"Temperance movement\",\"Progressive movement\",\"Abolitionist movement\",\"Free love movement\",\"Transcendentalism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc360491-9d28-4c83-a3cf-685e8ed3d82f",
    "question": "What was the purpose of the Marshall Plan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rebuild Western Europe after WWII",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fund the Vietnam War\",\"Establish NATO\",\"Create the United Nations\",\"Defend against Soviet expansion\",\"Develop nuclear weapons\",\"Space exploration\",\"End the Great Depression\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e42a741c-0026-422d-9d27-b08fce1bcc20",
    "question": "Who wrote the Communist Manifesto?",
    "correctAnswer": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vladimir Lenin\",\"Joseph Stalin\",\"Leon Trotsky\",\"Mao Zedong\",\"Fidel Castro\",\"Ho Chi Minh\",\"Che Guevara\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e619b56f-bd23-41b7-b083-3da397f679e9",
    "question": "Which city hosted the first modern Olympic Games?",
    "correctAnswer": "Athens",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Paris\",\"London\",\"Rome\",\"Berlin\",\"Tokyo\",\"Moscow\",\"Los Angeles\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "726fac5f-642f-411c-820c-a077f7fc7168",
    "question": "What disease caused a pandemic in 1918-1920?",
    "correctAnswer": "Spanish flu",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bubonic plague\",\"Smallpox\",\"Cholera\",\"Typhoid fever\",\"Polio\",\"COVID-19\",\"Yellow fever\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5abfaf4f-38ee-4686-a23a-6f1ca5ff5983",
    "question": "Who was the Japanese Emperor during World War II?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hirohito",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tojo\",\"Meiji\",\"Akihito\",\"Naruhito\",\"Taisho\",\"Showa\",\"Heisei\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "88834a12-58a1-4577-991c-a80a217f09a7",
    "question": "What event ended the Cold War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fall of the Soviet Union",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Cuban Missile Crisis\",\"Vietnam War\",\"Korean War\",\"Berlin Wall fall\",\"Space Race\",\"Nixon's China visit\",\"Helsinki Accords\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e99c2dd4-a4ef-4fa7-9c18-83af5d23515f",
    "question": "What was the first country to industrialize?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Britain",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"France\",\"United States\",\"Germany\",\"Japan\",\"Russia\",\"Italy\",\"Belgium\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d844391b-7b2f-4d59-8cb6-9c27d879b41a",
    "question": "Which leader abolished slavery in the US?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abraham Lincoln",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George Washington\",\"Thomas Jefferson\",\"Andrew Jackson\",\"Theodore Roosevelt\",\"Ulysses S. Grant\",\"Franklin D. Roosevelt\",\"John F. Kennedy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b76cd450-14c4-48cb-9a01-01191f93ad83",
    "question": "What were the opposing sides in the Cold War?",
    "correctAnswer": "USA and USSR",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Britain and Germany\",\"North and South Korea\",\"China and Japan\",\"France and England\",\"NATO and Warsaw Pact\",\"Israel and Palestine\",\"India and Pakistan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "162d5581-064c-4e7a-b718-52a625eb4f2b",
    "question": "What was the first artificial satellite?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sputnik 1",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Explorer 1\",\"Vanguard 1\",\"Apollo 11\",\"Hubble\",\"Voyager\",\"Telstar\",\"Mir\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "49905490-6978-4bd4-999f-76e2490b7323",
    "question": "Which country did the US fight in the War of 1812?",
    "correctAnswer": "Great Britain",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"France\",\"Spain\",\"Mexico\",\"Canada\",\"Germany\",\"Russia\",\"Japan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "47705a02-3bb2-4b7e-a74a-b7d8c9ca836f",
    "question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of Britain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Margaret Thatcher",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Theresa May\",\"Elizabeth II\",\"Queen Victoria\",\"Angela Merkel\",\"Indira Gandhi\",\"Golda Meir\",\"Hillary Clinton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "84483176-12ce-4b7d-b888-ddf490c57aad",
    "question": "What major event occurred in Chernobyl in 1986?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nuclear disaster",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Earthquake\",\"Military coup\",\"Olympic Games\",\"Civil war\",\"Peace treaty\",\"Independence declaration\",\"Revolution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4fce418-bd71-4c12-9c40-c8215ecbfa99",
    "question": "What was the first commercially successful airplane?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wright Flyer",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Boeing 707\",\"Concorde\",\"DC-3\",\"Airbus A300\",\"Supermarine Spitfire\",\"B-17 Flying Fortress\",\"Lockheed Constellation\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d143371-9c6e-4b55-9b44-4380df41d7f0",
    "question": "What was the nickname for America's 1920s?",
    "correctAnswer": "Roaring Twenties",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Progressive Era\",\"Great Depression\",\"Gilded Age\",\"Jazz Age\",\"Prohibition Era\",\"Lost Generation\",\"Reconstruction Era\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3575de26-ede2-4992-960e-1eba37950ed1",
    "question": "Which power led the Allied forces in WWII?",
    "correctAnswer": "United States",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Soviet Union\",\"Great Britain\",\"France\",\"China\",\"Canada\",\"Australia\",\"Poland\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0355c2b3-5769-4413-9bde-3a3cf27658fa",
    "question": "What 1803 purchase doubled the size of the USA?",
    "correctAnswer": "Louisiana Purchase",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alaska Purchase\",\"Gadsden Purchase\",\"Florida Purchase\",\"Texas Annexation\",\"Mexican Cession\",\"Oregon Territory\",\"California Acquisition\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "432eb079-ea44-4ccf-8088-46e5807a6545",
    "question": "Which country was first to use paper money?",
    "correctAnswer": "China",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"United States\",\"England\",\"France\",\"Germany\",\"Italy\",\"Japan\",\"India\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc2a5c6e-93df-4fed-9622-1d8e346be161",
    "question": "What major conflict began in 1950?",
    "correctAnswer": "Korean War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vietnam War\",\"World War II\",\"Gulf War\",\"Cold War\",\"Falklands War\",\"Iraq War\",\"Afghanistan War\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "02301c08-6f3a-4b57-a8f9-c2fd60fa5746",
    "question": "Who invented the steam engine?",
    "correctAnswer": "James Watt",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Alexander Bell\",\"Henry Ford\",\"Eli Whitney\",\"George Stephenson\",\"Robert Fulton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "af420821-c18c-4173-b9ec-51e1f81a8c78",
    "question": "What famous speech began with 'I have a dream'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Martin Luther King Jr.'s speech",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gettysburg Address\",\"Kennedy's Inaugural\",\"Nixon's Resignation\",\"Reagan's Berlin Wall\",\"Churchill's Iron Curtain\",\"Obama's Victory\",\"Roosevelt's Four Freedoms\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa847151-dd2a-44d0-bdba-0c29ec48b915",
    "question": "What was invented by Johannes Gutenberg?",
    "correctAnswer": "Printing press with movable type",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Light bulb\",\"Radio\",\"Computer\",\"Television\",\"Steam engine\",\"Automobile\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "31b2f677-f498-447e-b35e-3b586c0f80a2",
    "question": "Which nation developed the first atomic bomb?",
    "correctAnswer": "United States",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Soviet Union\",\"Germany\",\"Japan\",\"United Kingdom\",\"France\",\"China\",\"Israel\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:48:24.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "27772a49-48be-401b-bbd1-d650d035cce2",
    "question": "Which Russian tsar was overthrown in the 1917 Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nicholas II",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander III\",\"Ivan the Terrible\",\"Peter the Great\",\"Catherine the Great\",\"Alexander II\",\"Paul I\",\"Nicholas I\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "37f45f6a-fdfc-4f51-87be-bdb5d8c5fd3f",
    "question": "What treaty officially ended World War I?",
    "correctAnswer": "Treaty of Versailles",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Treaty of Paris\",\"Treaty of Brest-Litovsk\",\"Treaty of Trianon\",\"Treaty of Sevres\",\"Treaty of Lausanne\",\"Treaty of London\",\"Treaty of Saint-Germain\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d001991-6b42-4f7d-a357-6bd9b5588fe4",
    "question": "Who assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gavrilo Princip",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nedeljko Čabrinović\",\"Trifko Grabež\",\"Danilo Ilić\",\"Vladimir Gaćinović\",\"Muhamed Mehmedbašić\",\"Cvjetko Popović\",\"Vaso Čubrilović\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2444225b-32c3-4c01-9942-6e15f4a86a28",
    "question": "Which battle was Napoleon's final defeat?",
    "correctAnswer": "Waterloo",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Austerlitz\",\"Leipzig\",\"Trafalgar\",\"Borodino\",\"Jena\",\"Wagram\",\"Marengo\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f2bf9e0-8461-4f8e-bfc1-eadc0266e3bd",
    "question": "What was the political ideology of the Bolsheviks?",
    "correctAnswer": "Communism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fascism\",\"Democracy\",\"Monarchy\",\"Republicanism\",\"Anarchism\",\"Liberalism\",\"Conservatism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6795c89d-8130-4157-ab51-70ed998069d2",
    "question": "When did the Spanish Civil War end?",
    "correctAnswer": "1939",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1936\",\"1942\",\"1945\",\"1933\",\"1937\",\"1940\",\"1931\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e5cea86-52a7-4fcf-858b-b1b4c618c1b2",
    "question": "Which country was ruled by Benito Mussolini?",
    "correctAnswer": "Italy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Germany\",\"Spain\",\"Portugal\",\"Greece\",\"France\",\"Romania\",\"Hungary\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d59c1a34-7dd9-4e5b-aad4-7149678610c4",
    "question": "What was the Manhattan Project designed to develop?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nuclear weapons",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Skyscrapers\",\"Subway systems\",\"Space program\",\"Aircraft carriers\",\"Computer technology\",\"Penicillin production\",\"Radar technology\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cdec71c8-29d1-4a16-bbc2-ee0558c82a5c",
    "question": "What canal did Egypt nationalize in 1956?",
    "correctAnswer": "Suez Canal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Panama Canal\",\"Kiel Canal\",\"Grand Canal\",\"Corinth Canal\",\"Erie Canal\",\"Welland Canal\",\"Gota Canal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb5c739f-5cf1-46ee-a9dd-53b0cd881fe1",
    "question": "Which monarch reigned during the American Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "George III",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George II\",\"George IV\",\"Victoria\",\"Charles II\",\"William IV\",\"James II\",\"Anne\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3cd9d11d-8afb-4abd-8ee2-d3bd98ca2258",
    "question": "What crisis occurred during Kennedy's presidency?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cuban Missile Crisis",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Oil Crisis\",\"Iran Hostage Crisis\",\"Suez Crisis\",\"Berlin Blockade\",\"Vietnam War\",\"Watergate Scandal\",\"Great Depression\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9da22c5-97b9-4ec3-96c1-1397466b1844",
    "question": "What was the first communist state?",
    "correctAnswer": "Soviet Union",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"China\",\"Cuba\",\"Vietnam\",\"North Korea\",\"Yugoslavia\",\"Cambodia\",\"East Germany\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "43a7cbe2-ecf5-400e-b009-43bb14548d24",
    "question": "When did the Great Depression begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "1929",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1919\",\"1933\",\"1939\",\"1925\",\"1942\",\"1945\",\"1936\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9d5dc7c-ce1a-46be-a560-bcbc9b3f7285",
    "question": "Which US President established the Peace Corps?",
    "correctAnswer": "John F. Kennedy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Lyndon B. Johnson\",\"Richard Nixon\",\"Jimmy Carter\",\"Ronald Reagan\",\"Dwight Eisenhower\",\"Harry Truman\",\"Gerald Ford\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b965445-4838-4d63-aa56-db2b567bde3c",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union during WWII?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joseph Stalin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vladimir Lenin\",\"Leon Trotsky\",\"Nikita Khrushchev\",\"Mikhail Gorbachev\",\"Leonid Brezhnev\",\"Yuri Andropov\",\"Konstantin Chernenko\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "64a0c184-e625-4e33-a9e1-c694c0879910",
    "question": "What was the name of the US space program?",
    "correctAnswer": "Apollo",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gemini\",\"Mercury\",\"Voyager\",\"Galileo\",\"Explorer\",\"Discovery\",\"Challenger\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc746dd8-3da6-482b-bcc5-054ac660337e",
    "question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of India?",
    "correctAnswer": "Indira Gandhi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sonia Gandhi\",\"Pratibha Patil\",\"Benazir Bhutto\",\"Golda Meir\",\"Margaret Thatcher\",\"Sirimavo Bandaranaike\",\"Corazon Aquino\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4e7b382-d0c4-4c96-bf64-0d1803873475",
    "question": "What event triggered the US entry into WWI?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zimmermann Telegram",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Lusitania sinking\",\"Assassination of Franz Ferdinand\",\"Russian Revolution\",\"Fall of France\",\"Invasion of Belgium\",\"Bombing of Pearl Harbor\",\"U-boat campaign\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ba0526e-e4eb-4835-b547-302a9ba6e881",
    "question": "What region did Germany annex in 1938?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sudetenland",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alsace-Lorraine\",\"Rhineland\",\"Prussia\",\"Saarland\",\"Silesia\",\"Austria\",\"Poland\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7703745d-c6d4-43a7-a615-da956bf27d57",
    "question": "What was the name of China's last dynasty?",
    "correctAnswer": "Qing",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ming\",\"Yuan\",\"Han\",\"Tang\",\"Song\",\"Jin\",\"Zhou\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "712be7f7-7f51-48ce-b154-1d72df3f3d65",
    "question": "Who led the Cuban Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fidel Castro",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Che Guevara\",\"Raul Castro\",\"Fulgencio Batista\",\"José Martí\",\"Camilo Cienfuegos\",\"Frank País\",\"Huber Matos\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "40f979c4-842b-4576-a408-36acb67bb6d8",
    "question": "When was the European Union established?",
    "correctAnswer": "1993",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1957\",\"1945\",\"1973\",\"1986\",\"2002\",\"1950\",\"1967\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "606dea01-a088-493d-8389-b542bd1ae5d7",
    "question": "What ideological conflict defined the Cold War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Capitalism vs. Communism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Democracy vs. Fascism\",\"Freedom vs. Tyranny\",\"East vs. West\",\"NATO vs. Warsaw Pact\",\"US vs. USSR\",\"Liberty vs. Equality\",\"Republic vs. Monarchy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a555ad5d-f2c1-4594-99a4-93e3eab76418",
    "question": "Who founded the Red Cross?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henri Dunant",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Clara Barton\",\"Florence Nightingale\",\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Albert Schweitzer\",\"Elizabeth Blackwell\",\"Dorothea Dix\",\"Mary Seacole\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d50ffb3-8b3d-4d62-af16-f82a5912dd6b",
    "question": "What event in 1989 symbolized the end of communism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fall of the Berlin Wall",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tiananmen Square protests\",\"Soviet-Afghan War end\",\"Velvet Revolution\",\"Dissolution of USSR\",\"Fall of Ceaușescu\",\"Solidarity movement\",\"Polish elections\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f46e6c5c-cd9f-4a5c-8314-921d6035b011",
    "question": "Which nation was partitioned in 1947?",
    "correctAnswer": "India",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Korea\",\"Vietnam\",\"China\",\"Germany\",\"Yugoslavia\",\"Palestine\",\"Austria\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "86d31ebb-2fd3-422f-a422-532fe3eda2db",
    "question": "What was the first battle of the American Civil War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fort Sumter",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bull Run\",\"Antietam\",\"Gettysburg\",\"Shiloh\",\"Vicksburg\",\"Chancellorsville\",\"Appomattox\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce97f958-3669-4287-b22c-644c886c8020",
    "question": "Which US Supreme Court case addressed segregation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Brown v. Board of Education",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Roe v. Wade\",\"Miranda v. Arizona\",\"Plessy v. Ferguson\",\"Marbury v. Madison\",\"Gideon v. Wainwright\",\"Dred Scott v. Sandford\",\"Korematsu v. United States\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a734f92e-c317-4130-9406-b47784cdd844",
    "question": "What economic system did Adam Smith advocate?",
    "correctAnswer": "Capitalism",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Communism\",\"Socialism\",\"Mercantilism\",\"Feudalism\",\"Imperialism\",\"Fascism\",\"Anarchism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb46b9c2-f023-481c-ae7f-1f16633eab47",
    "question": "What territories did the US gain from the Mexican War?",
    "correctAnswer": "California and New Mexico",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Texas and Florida\",\"Oregon and Washington\",\"Alaska and Hawaii\",\"Puerto Rico and Guam\",\"Arizona and Nevada\",\"Louisiana and Arkansas\",\"Colorado and Utah\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1081ccc-40cd-4d3c-b2fb-46b9c37f2101",
    "question": "What revolution began in 1789?",
    "correctAnswer": "French Revolution",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"American Revolution\",\"Industrial Revolution\",\"Russian Revolution\",\"Chinese Revolution\",\"Cuban Revolution\",\"Mexican Revolution\",\"Iranian Revolution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8032088e-5d8d-4a1a-ac7c-8d050317ee33",
    "question": "Which German field marshal led the Africa Corps?",
    "correctAnswer": "Erwin Rommel",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Heinz Guderian\",\"Gerd von Rundstedt\",\"Erich von Manstein\",\"Wilhelm Keitel\",\"Friedrich Paulus\",\"Albert Kesselring\",\"Karl Dönitz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "11cf7f44-c646-46c9-b910-658bb7f7ef96",
    "question": "What US program fought the Great Depression?",
    "correctAnswer": "New Deal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marshall Plan\",\"Great Society\",\"Fair Deal\",\"New Freedom\",\"Square Deal\",\"New Frontier\",\"War on Poverty\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5302a7b-a050-47a6-890c-9c1747cf3e09",
    "question": "What year did the Crimean War begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "1853",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1841\",\"1866\",\"1878\",\"1830\",\"1812\",\"1871\",\"1848\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1dfd6f1e-bc81-45c9-8b45-0d90058adfc9",
    "question": "What major innovation did Henry Ford introduce?",
    "correctAnswer": "Assembly line",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Steam engine\",\"Electric light\",\"Telegraph\",\"Telephone\",\"Airplane\",\"Radio\",\"Automobile\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b01b9bc-6d67-4358-a90f-68a7b212b512",
    "question": "What policy sought to contain communism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Truman Doctrine",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Monroe Doctrine\",\"Marshall Plan\",\"Eisenhower Doctrine\",\"Reagan Doctrine\",\"Nixon Doctrine\",\"Carter Doctrine\",\"Bush Doctrine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac4b578e-8ca4-4031-9a4e-9c585cf45121",
    "question": "Who led the Long March in China?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mao Zedong",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Chiang Kai-shek\",\"Sun Yat-sen\",\"Zhou Enlai\",\"Deng Xiaoping\",\"Yuan Shikai\",\"Li Zongren\",\"Puyi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0dba9752-2171-4b79-9a5c-95826bf3e557",
    "question": "What was the Russo-Japanese War about?",
    "correctAnswer": "Control of Manchuria and Korea",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Baltic sea access\",\"Control of Central Asia\",\"Oil resources\",\"Religious conflict\",\"Communist revolution\",\"Trade routes\",\"Naval supremacy\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "89fc4063-9905-4fa3-8ff0-5415e8ed821d",
    "question": "Which country was formed after WWI?",
    "correctAnswer": "Czechoslovakia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Soviet Union\",\"Yugoslavia\",\"Germany\",\"Austria\",\"Poland\",\"Hungary\",\"Romania\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c56c1476-623c-45c7-b3c4-c203bcbac14e",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the Viet Cong?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ho Chi Minh",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ngo Dinh Diem\",\"Vo Nguyen Giap\",\"Pol Pot\",\"Bao Dai\",\"Nguyen Van Thieu\",\"Le Duan\",\"Pham Van Dong\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d1b0ef4c-6574-46ea-b97e-e71b9e68cb1e",
    "question": "What battle was the turning point of WWII Pacific War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Midway",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pearl Harbor\",\"Guadalcanal\",\"Iwo Jima\",\"Okinawa\",\"Leyte Gulf\",\"Coral Sea\",\"Philippines Sea\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "439c9ac3-39d8-4c4d-9a3a-8553ee5a8ce4",
    "question": "What was the Zimmermann Telegram?",
    "correctAnswer": "German proposal to Mexico",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Peace offer to Britain\",\"Alliance with Japan\",\"Declaration of war\",\"Submarine warfare notice\",\"Colonial dispute\",\"Spy communication\",\"Armistice terms\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "66bb9661-a4c0-4830-a72f-dae80f9cad57",
    "question": "What was the goal of the Boxer Rebellion?",
    "correctAnswer": "Expel foreigners from China",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Overthrow Qing Dynasty\",\"Support communism\",\"Establish republic\",\"Promote Christianity\",\"Open trade ports\",\"Restore Ming Dynasty\",\"End opium trade\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b118e289-b81a-4ada-96dd-61ac0f441df7",
    "question": "Which countries fought the Falklands War?",
    "correctAnswer": "UK and Argentina",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"US and Cuba\",\"France and Germany\",\"Spain and Portugal\",\"Brazil and Uruguay\",\"Chile and Peru\",\"Russia and Japan\",\"China and Vietnam\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "787d1d4e-9369-4fef-b983-06ef66512bfd",
    "question": "What policy of racial segregation ruled South Africa?",
    "correctAnswer": "Apartheid",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jim Crow\",\"Caste system\",\"Colonialism\",\"Imperialism\",\"Ethnic cleansing\",\"Separate development\",\"Racial purity\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5802e7f-57b2-41c3-bbfc-cc534bba6eef",
    "question": "In which city was JFK assassinated?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dallas",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Houston\",\"Austin\",\"San Antonio\",\"Washington DC\",\"New York\",\"Boston\",\"Chicago\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "660af509-35eb-4042-8565-3a732d0fab48",
    "question": "What caused the Irish Potato Famine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Potato blight",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Drought\",\"British policies\",\"Civil war\",\"Industrialization\",\"Overpopulation\",\"Trade restrictions\",\"Land redistribution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ae4e21a2-af85-4252-8c2d-12f8c5d6a0d3",
    "question": "Who was the first Chancellor of unified Germany?",
    "correctAnswer": "Otto von Bismarck",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Kaiser Wilhelm I\",\"Friedrich Ebert\",\"Adolf Hitler\",\"Konrad Adenauer\",\"Helmut Kohl\",\"Willy Brandt\",\"Angela Merkel\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b322992-e841-4bc0-adf2-6cc8816a4350",
    "question": "What was the Reign of Terror?",
    "correctAnswer": "Period of executions in French Revolution",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Russian purges\",\"Spanish Inquisition\",\"Nazi Holocaust\",\"Chinese Cultural Revolution\",\"Cambodian genocide\",\"Ottoman massacres\",\"Stalinist repression\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "968c59a3-1c7c-42f3-95ec-8d855fa154d6",
    "question": "What year did South Africa end apartheid?",
    "correctAnswer": "1994",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1984\",\"1989\",\"1991\",\"1976\",\"2000\",\"1980\",\"1986\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "82436724-9d07-4b19-9f93-3097bd996bb8",
    "question": "What was the purpose of the Monroe Doctrine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Prevent European colonization in Americas",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Expand US territory\",\"Promote free trade\",\"Establish naval dominance\",\"Form American alliances\",\"Isolate from world affairs\",\"Oppose communism\",\"Support Latin American independence\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a32745f7-35c5-4413-b3d4-588c33517f93",
    "question": "What African country resisted European colonization?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ethiopia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egypt\",\"South Africa\",\"Nigeria\",\"Libya\",\"Algeria\",\"Morocco\",\"Kenya\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e065bd0d-9e75-4b2f-aa4e-d26b9b8cb7b9",
    "question": "Who was the leader of Italian unification?",
    "correctAnswer": "Giuseppe Garibaldi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Camillo di Cavour\",\"Victor Emmanuel II\",\"Giuseppe Mazzini\",\"Pope Pius IX\",\"Napoleon III\",\"Umberto I\",\"Francesco Crispi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6cf15efc-bc50-4a65-9db1-504ecb1ad597",
    "question": "What treaty gave control of the Philippines to the US?",
    "correctAnswer": "Treaty of Paris",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Treaty of Versailles\",\"Treaty of Tordesillas\",\"Treaty of Utrecht\",\"Treaty of Ghent\",\"Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo\",\"Treaty of Portsmouth\",\"Treaty of San Francisco\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "df5f547a-ff12-4e23-8259-035087e8fbd1",
    "question": "Which country did the US acquire from Russia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alaska",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hawaii\",\"Puerto Rico\",\"Guam\",\"Philippines\",\"Cuba\",\"Panama\",\"Virgin Islands\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:52:26.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6bf4f2d-86a3-45b6-9f05-6481363d556b",
    "question": "Which treaty transferred Alsace-Lorraine back to France?",
    "correctAnswer": "Treaty of Versailles",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Treaty of Frankfurt\",\"Treaty of Trianon\",\"Treaty of Brest-Litovsk\",\"Treaty of Saint-Germain\",\"Treaty of Neuilly\",\"Treaty of Sèvres\",\"Treaty of Lausanne\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "43e2c5ce-bc91-49e8-863c-e5039d68fd73",
    "question": "Who commanded the HMS Beagle during Darwin's voyage?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robert FitzRoy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Cook\",\"William Bligh\",\"George Vancouver\",\"Francis Drake\",\"Matthew Flinders\",\"James Clark Ross\",\"John Franklin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c19e01ea-a00d-4a43-8bec-cafee85e2d75",
    "question": "Which country did not attend the Congress of Vienna?",
    "correctAnswer": "United States",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Austria\",\"Prussia\",\"Russia\",\"Great Britain\",\"France\",\"Spain\",\"Sweden\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "df8a117d-a05b-43f4-b629-d5bdfe1e76fb",
    "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
    "correctAnswer": "John A. Macdonald",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Mackenzie\",\"Wilfrid Laurier\",\"Robert Borden\",\"William Lyon Mackenzie King\",\"John Diefenbaker\",\"Pierre Trudeau\",\"Louis St. Laurent\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "910c2e5a-8a1d-4a39-8300-d931ec23cc46",
    "question": "What was the 'February Patent' in Austrian history?",
    "correctAnswer": "Constitutional document",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Trade agreement\",\"Military alliance\",\"Banking regulation\",\"Land reform law\",\"Religious decree\",\"Postal service creation\",\"Educational reform\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "51a5453c-f774-4bf2-b882-5f38bf86f37a",
    "question": "What year did Belgium gain independence?",
    "correctAnswer": "1830",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1815\",\"1848\",\"1871\",\"1789\",\"1861\",\"1905\",\"1919\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3647922-8a37-4a01-9f37-a3bccd61d453",
    "question": "Who was the only unmarried US President?",
    "correctAnswer": "James Buchanan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Grover Cleveland\",\"Andrew Jackson\",\"Woodrow Wilson\",\"Chester Arthur\",\"Calvin Coolidge\",\"Herbert Hoover\",\"Franklin Pierce\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ce3e75e-0c89-4b8a-b871-cc4b483d4ba0",
    "question": "Which city hosted the secret Manhattan Project lab?",
    "correctAnswer": "Los Alamos",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Oak Ridge\",\"Chicago\",\"Hanford\",\"Berkeley\",\"Princeton\",\"San Francisco\",\"Washington D.C.\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "697c4d48-00a3-40dc-81c1-4e229b0b1445",
    "question": "What was the name of Lenin's revolutionary newspaper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Iskra",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pravda\",\"Izvestia\",\"Novaya Zhizn\",\"Vperyod\",\"Zvezda\",\"Rabochaya Gazeta\",\"Borba\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3b4d7c1-6db4-4665-ac47-2cfd3ead314c",
    "question": "Who was the French foreign minister behind European integration?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robert Schuman",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jean Monnet\",\"René Pleven\",\"Georges Bidault\",\"Maurice Schumann\",\"Christian Pineau\",\"Antoine Pinay\",\"Guy Mollet\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "974770f1-90f1-4093-b655-1d03ff6bab18",
    "question": "What political movement did Giuseppe Mazzini found?",
    "correctAnswer": "Young Italy",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Carbonari\",\"Risorgimento\",\"Red Shirts\",\"National Society\",\"Italian Fascism\",\"Black Hand\",\"Irredentism\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "65874f48-013e-4eb4-8f38-22e7ceea0a91",
    "question": "Which Bolshevik led the Soviet secret police?",
    "correctAnswer": "Felix Dzerzhinsky",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Lavrentiy Beria\",\"Nikolai Yezhov\",\"Genrikh Yagoda\",\"Vyacheslav Menzhinsky\",\"Rudolf Abel\",\"Ivan Serov\",\"Alexander Shelepin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b16580b-9f61-4c8a-bbea-cb922648dc85",
    "question": "Who was the last Emperor of Austria-Hungary?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles I",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Franz Joseph I\",\"Ferdinand I\",\"Leopold II\",\"Francis II\",\"Joseph II\",\"Ferdinand Maximilian\",\"Otto von Habsburg\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "abb5921b-0ec1-468a-89e3-396cac001fb0",
    "question": "What was the codename for the Allied invasion of Sicily?",
    "correctAnswer": "Operation Husky",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Operation Overlord\",\"Operation Torch\",\"Operation Barbarossa\",\"Operation Market Garden\",\"Operation Dragoon\",\"Operation Avalanche\",\"Operation Cobra\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "166380c9-900d-46fe-a9c8-04c2b0513e00",
    "question": "Who led the 1954 Guatemalan coup?",
    "correctAnswer": "Carlos Castillo Armas",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jacobo Árbenz\",\"Juan José Arévalo\",\"Miguel Ydígoras\",\"Efraín Ríos Montt\",\"Romeo Lucas García\",\"Jorge Ubico\",\"José María Orellana\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "47afbb0f-71fa-484b-bcfd-10050c44d39b",
    "question": "Which African country was formerly called Abyssinia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ethiopia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Somalia\",\"Eritrea\",\"Djibouti\",\"Sudan\",\"Kenya\",\"Tanzania\",\"Egypt\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fef90701-62fc-4257-bfde-3404c315790c",
    "question": "Who was French president during the Algerian independence?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles de Gaulle",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Georges Pompidou\",\"Vincent Auriol\",\"René Coty\",\"François Mitterrand\",\"Valéry Giscard d'Estaing\",\"Jacques Chirac\",\"Georges Clemenceau\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "45c7e0fc-bdaf-4fb1-a4b5-2297e47df258",
    "question": "What was the 1962 US-Cuba confrontation called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cuban Missile Crisis",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bay of Pigs Invasion\",\"Operation Mongoose\",\"Project Azorian\",\"Operation Northwoods\",\"Mariel boatlift\",\"Havana Harbor incident\",\"Platt Amendment crisis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a83066e4-b35e-40d9-8e99-26a3e4fcdf16",
    "question": "Who assassinated Austrian Archduke Franz Ferdinand?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gavrilo Princip",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nedeljko Čabrinović\",\"Trifko Grabež\",\"Danilo Ilić\",\"Muhamed Mehmedbašić\",\"Cvjetko Popović\",\"Vaso Čubrilović\",\"Lazar Đukić\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9944a62-eae6-4db5-9098-7e1ba59cda86",
    "question": "Which country was neutral in both World Wars?",
    "correctAnswer": "Switzerland",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sweden\",\"Spain\",\"Portugal\",\"Turkey\",\"Argentina\",\"Ireland\",\"Chile\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "604a0c95-6cb6-4740-97d3-d0f8408e9dd5",
    "question": "What was Chiang Kai-shek's political party?",
    "correctAnswer": "Kuomintang",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Communist Party\",\"Democratic Progressive Party\",\"New Power Party\",\"China Democratic League\",\"China Zhi Gong Party\",\"Taiwanese People's Party\",\"People First Party\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6de19c2-9afe-427c-8af2-0bbf20cae1d8",
    "question": "Who was the last viceroy of India?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lord Mountbatten",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Lord Wavell\",\"Lord Linlithgow\",\"Lord Willingdon\",\"Lord Irwin\",\"Lord Reading\",\"Lord Chelmsford\",\"Lord Hardinge\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0115cd9f-b44d-4ec6-915c-821a4f53c382",
    "question": "What military alliance opposed NATO during Cold War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Warsaw Pact",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"SEATO\",\"CENTO\",\"Comecon\",\"Cominform\",\"ANZUS\",\"Rio Pact\",\"Baghdad Pact\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c26879b5-d60c-46d9-8220-be3f0bc3a520",
    "question": "Where was imprisoned Nelson Mandela for 18 years?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robben Island",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pollsmoor Prison\",\"Victor Verster Prison\",\"Pretoria Central\",\"Johannesburg Prison\",\"Durban Westville\",\"Fort Glamorgan\",\"St. Helena Island\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "374afe9f-9ea6-4f67-af59-8c79586ca5ef",
    "question": "Which country was called Siam until 1939?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thailand",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Myanmar\",\"Cambodia\",\"Laos\",\"Vietnam\",\"Malaysia\",\"Indonesia\",\"Philippines\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a36621ad-2af0-4f73-a5ee-dbcd0f42b271",
    "question": "What was the name of Hitler's economic recovery plan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Four Year Plan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"New Deal\",\"Five Year Plan\",\"Marshall Plan\",\"Dawes Plan\",\"Young Plan\",\"Morgenthau Plan\",\"Schacht Plan\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd3db6b4-a3f7-4f03-8fe8-5bca9a17157e",
    "question": "Who led the first successful climb of Mount Everest?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edmund Hillary",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Tenzing Norgay\",\"George Mallory\",\"Reinhold Messner\",\"Chris Bonington\",\"Robert Falcon Scott\",\"Ernest Shackleton\",\"Roald Amundsen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "35fbdb8e-648e-4308-86d8-6479b11b10a0",
    "question": "What was the first combat jet aircraft?",
    "correctAnswer": "Messerschmitt Me 262",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gloster Meteor\",\"P-80 Shooting Star\",\"Heinkel He 178\",\"MiG-15\",\"Saab 21R\",\"De Havilland Vampire\",\"Arado Ar 234\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2afd7f2-8889-4eef-bea3-dcc20214ebe9",
    "question": "What empire did Japan defeat in its first modern war?",
    "correctAnswer": "Qing China",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Russian Empire\",\"British Empire\",\"Ottoman Empire\",\"Korean Empire\",\"French Empire\",\"Dutch Empire\",\"Portuguese Empire\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d911b815-30d0-46be-af85-5badbf8fef48",
    "question": "Who authored the book 'Das Kapital'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Karl Marx",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Friedrich Engels\",\"Vladimir Lenin\",\"Rosa Luxemburg\",\"Leon Trotsky\",\"Antonio Gramsci\",\"Georg Hegel\",\"Max Weber\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9870861d-a0bd-4150-b5ff-69cb1cf3ed8c",
    "question": "What shipbuilding center did Japan attack in 1941?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pearl Harbor",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"San Diego\",\"Norfolk\",\"Bremerton\",\"Long Beach\",\"Yokosuka\",\"Manila\",\"Singapore\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb04b9de-bbab-4abe-8075-895a087d4df3",
    "question": "Which Italian leader founded the Fascist Party?",
    "correctAnswer": "Benito Mussolini",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Victor Emmanuel III\",\"Giovanni Giolitti\",\"Antonio Salandra\",\"Sidney Sonnino\",\"Luigi Facta\",\"Ivanoe Bonomi\",\"Gabriele D'Annunzio\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e3db5cf-030c-47c7-85b3-adbc47adb603",
    "question": "What revolution began with the April Theses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Russian Revolution",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"French Revolution\",\"Chinese Revolution\",\"Cuban Revolution\",\"Iranian Revolution\",\"Mexican Revolution\",\"Turkish Revolution\",\"Romanian Revolution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "436743a4-3e46-4870-98c9-a5c8f09d9042",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical telephone?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexander Graham Bell",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Elisha Gray\",\"Antonio Meucci\",\"Johann Philipp Reis\",\"Innocenzo Manzetti\",\"Charles Bourseul\",\"Tivadar Puskás\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ecf5749-5d44-4fd7-a688-799ce24ad0ff",
    "question": "What was Wilson's post-WWI peace program called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fourteen Points",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"New Freedom\",\"Square Deal\",\"New Nationalism\",\"Great Society\",\"Fair Deal\",\"New Frontier\",\"New Deal\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b609fdd-fadd-4a42-a6a1-8e4768c4d45c",
    "question": "What rebellion occurred in British India in 1857?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sepoy Mutiny",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Quit India Movement\",\"Salt March\",\"Chittagong Uprising\",\"Moplah Rebellion\",\"Vellore Mutiny\",\"Santhal Rebellion\",\"Sikh Rebellion\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e55afbf-1854-4ce3-a76d-572949b7464b",
    "question": "Which country did NOT participate in the Berlin Conference?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ethiopia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Great Britain\",\"France\",\"Germany\",\"Belgium\",\"Portugal\",\"Italy\",\"United States\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4162bef6-ecbc-47a6-bd9b-097a59834311",
    "question": "Who was the architect of German unification?",
    "correctAnswer": "Otto von Bismarck",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Kaiser Wilhelm I\",\"Friedrich Wilhelm IV\",\"Wilhelm II\",\"Friedrich III\",\"Heinrich von Gagern\",\"Karl vom Stein\",\"August von Gneisenau\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "456a828e-7ee3-434c-9f8a-e98c7cd2bd08",
    "question": "Which Chinese leader launched the Cultural Revolution?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mao Zedong",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Deng Xiaoping\",\"Zhou Enlai\",\"Liu Shaoqi\",\"Jiang Qing\",\"Lin Biao\",\"Hua Guofeng\",\"Chiang Kai-shek\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4350ebd4-b4a0-4615-b366-4aefbcba7f79",
    "question": "What was the first battle of WWI's Western Front?",
    "correctAnswer": "Battle of the Frontiers",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"First Battle of Marne\",\"Battle of Tannenberg\",\"Battle of Mons\",\"Battle of Charleroi\",\"Battle of Liège\",\"Battle of the Ardennes\",\"Battle of Mulhouse\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "88d9b67b-bcc4-4509-b614-e654cf09c7a5",
    "question": "Which military commander said 'I shall return'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Douglas MacArthur",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Dwight Eisenhower\",\"George Patton\",\"Chester Nimitz\",\"William Halsey\",\"Omar Bradley\",\"George Marshall\",\"Matthew Ridgway\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "acc75d22-a22b-40fa-a18c-a4bf9bcc41ce",
    "question": "Who negotiated the Camp David Accords?",
    "correctAnswer": "Carter, Begin, and Sadat",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nixon, Meir, and Sadat\",\"Bush, Sharon, and Mubarak\",\"Clinton, Rabin, and Arafat\",\"Reagan, Begin, and Mubarak\",\"Obama, Netanyahu, and Abbas\",\"Johnson, Eshkol, and Nasser\",\"Ford, Rabin, and Sadat\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9967733b-a4fb-477f-880f-9a1929366ad7",
    "question": "What conflict was sparked by the Ems Dispatch?",
    "correctAnswer": "Franco-Prussian War",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Seven Weeks' War\",\"Crimean War\",\"World War I\",\"War of 1870\",\"Second Schleswig War\",\"Austro-Prussian War\",\"Belgian Revolution\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d9125b2-32f7-4087-ae90-d666e227844a",
    "question": "Who coined the term 'Iron Curtain'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Winston Churchill",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Harry Truman\",\"Joseph Stalin\",\"Franklin Roosevelt\",\"George Kennan\",\"Joseph McCarthy\",\"Clement Attlee\",\"Dwight Eisenhower\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "313f82cd-7fdb-4208-acb2-1575140588ba",
    "question": "Which country left the European Union in 2020?",
    "correctAnswer": "United Kingdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sweden\",\"Denmark\",\"Finland\",\"Ireland\",\"Greece\",\"Portugal\",\"Croatia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6c09c0d-1bd1-417e-8942-8bd1dae9ed99",
    "question": "What African country defeated Italy at Adwa in 1896?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ethiopia",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Egypt\",\"Libya\",\"Somalia\",\"Sudan\",\"Eritrea\",\"Morocco\",\"Tunisia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5cfa8e7a-c701-4fe8-87b7-bac2ff50455c",
    "question": "Who was the first Japanese Prime Minister?",
    "correctAnswer": "Itō Hirobumi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Yamagata Aritomo\",\"Kuroda Kiyotaka\",\"Matsukata Masayoshi\",\"Saionji Kinmochi\",\"Ōkuma Shigenobu\",\"Katsura Tarō\",\"Yamamoto Gonbee\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7905bcf-fd8a-482a-9642-b77a39787686",
    "question": "Who founded the first Pan-African Congress?",
    "correctAnswer": "W.E.B. Du Bois",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marcus Garvey\",\"Kwame Nkrumah\",\"Jomo Kenyatta\",\"Nnamdi Azikiwe\",\"George Padmore\",\"Julius Nyerere\",\"Léopold Sédar Senghor\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cbb52b83-827e-4805-b506-b63d2b6fa2af",
    "question": "Which event began the Spanish-American War?",
    "correctAnswer": "USS Maine explosion",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Battle of Manila Bay\",\"Treaty of Paris\",\"Rough Riders charge\",\"Annexation of Hawaii\",\"Teller Amendment\",\"De Lôme Letter\",\"Battle of San Juan Hill\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d2c42e-dccc-4e68-bc00-50e628c01c5a",
    "question": "What was the SALT treaties' purpose?",
    "correctAnswer": "Limit strategic nuclear weapons",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Reduce conventional forces\",\"Ban biological weapons\",\"Prevent nuclear proliferation\",\"Establish trade relations\",\"Share space technology\",\"Prevent naval incidents\",\"Regulate arms exports\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "48f50151-4624-4d31-8789-4ece457c2d64",
    "question": "Which republic lasted just six days in 1939?",
    "correctAnswer": "Carpatho-Ukraine",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Slovak Republic\",\"Finnish Democratic Republic\",\"Albania\",\"Tatarstan\",\"Latvia\",\"Bessarabia\",\"Estonia\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b95fd995-24ed-4720-8199-aad413128e0d",
    "question": "Who was called the 'Father of Indian Constitution'?",
    "correctAnswer": "B.R. Ambedkar",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jawaharlal Nehru\",\"Mahatma Gandhi\",\"Vallabhbhai Patel\",\"Rajendra Prasad\",\"C. Rajagopalachari\",\"Maulana Azad\",\"Sarojini Naidu\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7972514a-1e7d-4d67-8062-32bfd2041493",
    "question": "Which naval battle decided the Russo-Japanese War?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tsushima",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Yellow Sea\",\"Port Arthur\",\"Chemulpo Bay\",\"Vladivostok\",\"Sea of Japan\",\"Sakhalin\",\"Mukden\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e86ad0d7-ad4f-468f-9ac1-80bfb19b5df9",
    "question": "What was the first international peace organization?",
    "correctAnswer": "League of Nations",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"United Nations\",\"International Court\",\"Hague Conventions\",\"NATO\",\"Warsaw Pact\",\"Permanent Court\",\"International Red Cross\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4303e280-a6fe-41fd-a273-bc5fa94ab96f",
    "question": "Who was the first non-royal head of France?",
    "correctAnswer": "Maximilien Robespierre",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Napoleon Bonaparte\",\"Georges Danton\",\"Jean-Paul Marat\",\"Camille Desmoulins\",\"Emmanuel Sieyès\",\"Lazare Carnot\",\"Louis Saint-Just\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6d192e3-fe06-44cc-9af8-e2acd2f98955",
    "question": "What movement overthrew Hawaiian Queen Liliuokalani?",
    "correctAnswer": "Committee of Safety",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"American Military\",\"Missionary Party\",\"Kingdom of Hawaii\",\"Provisional Government\",\"Republic of Hawaii\",\"Hawaiian League\",\"Reform Party\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Modern History",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T01:57:31.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7010d477-87af-4151-afc1-31b8c1053c73",
    "question": "Who invented the telephone?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexander Graham Bell",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Elisha Gray\",\"Antonio Meucci\",\"Samuel Morse\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e8cd4d5-8595-44be-9b9e-d18f8ff62795",
    "question": "What did Thomas Edison invent in 1879?",
    "correctAnswer": "Light bulb",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Radio\",\"Television\",\"Phonograph\",\"Telegraph\",\"Camera\",\"X-ray machine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "26ae1b96-2bfc-471a-baa5-d9436c1849b9",
    "question": "Which brothers invented the airplane?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wright brothers",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marx brothers\",\"Lumière brothers\",\"Warner brothers\",\"Grimm brothers\",\"Smith brothers\",\"Kellogg brothers\",\"Mayo brothers\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b65d0214-b434-44d4-9e54-25296bc94ba9",
    "question": "Who discovered penicillin?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexander Fleming",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Marie Curie\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Albert Einstein\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a46f85f-97d4-4e1b-8b51-0fbf0fece5bd",
    "question": "Who invented the World Wide Web?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tim Berners-Lee",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bill Gates\",\"Steve Jobs\",\"Mark Zuckerberg\",\"Larry Page\",\"Sergey Brin\",\"Alan Turing\",\"Vint Cerf\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f5003f9-104a-402c-86e1-d3c13e0770b1",
    "question": "What did Johannes Gutenberg invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Printing press",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telescope\",\"Microscope\",\"Compass\",\"Steam engine\",\"Wheel\",\"Clock\",\"Thermometer\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "385ff6c0-6503-49b0-8ff9-54c1c076245a",
    "question": "What device did Galileo invent to view distant objects?",
    "correctAnswer": "Telescope",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Microscope\",\"Camera\",\"Binoculars\",\"Compass\",\"Sextant\",\"Periscope\",\"Kaleidoscope\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5db7ac64-ef72-4cc7-b953-b3f7a6d0cd5c",
    "question": "Who invented dynamite?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alfred Nobel",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Albert Einstein\",\"Marie Curie\",\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"Dmitri Mendeleev\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "80565f1e-4906-4bbc-a3e4-b72026f715cb",
    "question": "What did Henry Ford revolutionize?",
    "correctAnswer": "Car manufacturing",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aviation\",\"Shipbuilding\",\"Computer industry\",\"Agriculture\",\"Medicine\",\"Telecommunications\",\"Electrical power\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe3e6ebc-5371-4826-a0e3-97a6c3a2dc82",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical photography?",
    "correctAnswer": "Louis Daguerre",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George Eastman\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Edwin Land\",\"Joseph Nicéphore Niépce\",\"Eadweard Muybridge\",\"Ansel Adams\",\"Henri Cartier-Bresson\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "83839fa6-a3ba-40bc-b419-83221cc989a9",
    "question": "What life-saving device did Percy Spencer invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Microwave oven",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Pacemaker\",\"Defibrillator\",\"X-ray machine\",\"MRI scanner\",\"Insulin pump\",\"Respirator\",\"Dialysis machine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "edcb3e2b-08a0-4bc7-ae44-a73c48154cef",
    "question": "Who invented the phonograph?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Edison",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Emile Berliner\",\"Lee de Forest\",\"Edwin Howard Armstrong\",\"John Logie Baird\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "679114a7-ad8f-434b-a24a-7771b5429252",
    "question": "What ancient Chinese invention was made of paper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Compass",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gunpowder\",\"Printing press\",\"Kite\",\"Porcelain\",\"Wheelbarrow\",\"Clock\",\"Seismoscope\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf27adbe-e1a9-4c74-9eff-23ba66f42449",
    "question": "Who invented the polio vaccine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jonas Salk",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Marie Curie\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Albert Sabin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b9463a1-7cee-4437-bfa6-b50a57490a2b",
    "question": "What did the Wright brothers invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Airplane",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Helicopter\",\"Hot air balloon\",\"Zeppelin\",\"Glider\",\"Jet engine\",\"Blimp\",\"Parachute\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d9e38e3-a8e3-4ad0-b402-f8ebdacb9524",
    "question": "Who discovered electricity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Benjamin Franklin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"James Watt\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Georg Ohm\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1620cbf7-9afe-4222-b5e8-d77f639d2c65",
    "question": "What food preservation method did Nicolas Appert invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Canning",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Freezing\",\"Dehydration\",\"Smoking\",\"Salting\",\"Pickling\",\"Pasteurization\",\"Freeze-drying\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "52a16630-7963-4507-978e-3a555b87aaf7",
    "question": "Who invented television?",
    "correctAnswer": "Philo Farnsworth",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"John Logie Baird\",\"Vladimir Zworykin\",\"Lee de Forest\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e2caf7f-304c-49a8-89aa-d9ae940ef82a",
    "question": "What ancient Chinese invention uses gunpowder?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fireworks",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Compass\",\"Paper\",\"Printing\",\"Silk\",\"Porcelain\",\"Abacus\",\"Crossbow\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "961967ef-fa09-4ae3-9772-a17a0a1dffdf",
    "question": "Who invented the first successful vaccine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edward Jenner",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Albert Sabin\",\"Marie Curie\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab8485c2-1bbc-4d65-a379-e3025b902791",
    "question": "What did Samuel Morse create a code for?",
    "correctAnswer": "Telegraph",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Radio\",\"Television\",\"Computer\",\"Internet\",\"Satellite\",\"Radar\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c0d1b1f-c2f7-4719-ba8d-02861da6923f",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical refrigerator?",
    "correctAnswer": "Carl von Linde",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Albert Einstein\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"James Harrison\",\"Willis Carrier\",\"Charles Kettering\",\"John Gorrie\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e044e2ba-7b22-4f8b-bc77-78c517b26f2d",
    "question": "Who invented the radio?",
    "correctAnswer": "Guglielmo Marconi",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"Lee de Forest\",\"Reginald Fessenden\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc949d03-fdd3-4dfa-86c8-14a5506426e6",
    "question": "What transportation method did Karl Benz invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Automobile",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bicycle\",\"Motorcycle\",\"Airplane\",\"Helicopter\",\"Train\",\"Submarine\",\"Zeppelin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b5d1e93-c6f8-4078-a432-700cee90e379",
    "question": "Who invented the first computer mouse?",
    "correctAnswer": "Douglas Engelbart",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Steve Jobs\",\"Bill Gates\",\"Alan Turing\",\"Ada Lovelace\",\"Tim Berners-Lee\",\"Charles Babbage\",\"John von Neumann\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4b043c6-7018-47a9-9462-177ff7fa8be1",
    "question": "What did Eli Whitney invent in 1794?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cotton gin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Sewing machine\",\"Spinning jenny\",\"Power loom\",\"Steam engine\",\"Threshing machine\",\"Reaper\",\"Combine harvester\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ae646d0-a4ff-42d1-950d-73cff1081654",
    "question": "Who discovered X-rays?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wilhelm Röntgen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marie Curie\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"Henri Becquerel\",\"Pierre Curie\",\"Max Planck\",\"Niels Bohr\",\"Albert Einstein\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5679cc99-3845-4b1a-81d3-c8161cd7377f",
    "question": "Who invented the battery?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alessandro Volta",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Michael Faraday\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"James Watt\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4346f37-5f99-419f-a66e-415cc015bc91",
    "question": "What weapon did Richard Gatling invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Machine gun",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Revolver\",\"Rifle\",\"Cannon\",\"Grenade\",\"Bayonet\",\"Tank\",\"Land mine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8e8d3ec0-3bf1-455a-bda2-29ad065d7cf7",
    "question": "Who invented the smallpox vaccine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edward Jenner",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Albert Sabin\",\"Marie Curie\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "14c1063d-1aa7-428c-9f7b-a0a43e3d2797",
    "question": "What did Laszlo Biro invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ballpoint pen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fountain pen\",\"Pencil\",\"Marker\",\"Typewriter\",\"Printer\",\"Highlighter\",\"Ink\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1547e791-6598-40ef-85f4-0348cb0c2ed7",
    "question": "Who invented the first mechanical calculator?",
    "correctAnswer": "Blaise Pascal",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Babbage\",\"Alan Turing\",\"Ada Lovelace\",\"John von Neumann\",\"Howard Aiken\",\"Gottfried Leibniz\",\"Wilhelm Schickard\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e1ea1f3-afb7-4f13-acb0-7e5cb1d76d67",
    "question": "Who invented the first successful electric light bulb?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Edison",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Joseph Swan\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"James Watt\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"Alessandro Volta\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "02fb4b2c-0197-4fac-956c-e1fced5e7c24",
    "question": "Who discovered gravity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isaac Newton",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Albert Einstein\",\"Galileo Galilei\",\"Nicolaus Copernicus\",\"Johannes Kepler\",\"Stephen Hawking\",\"Archimedes\",\"Aristotle\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f34106fe-b711-4ca2-aff1-af203f88ac27",
    "question": "What did Rudolf Diesel invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Diesel engine",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Gasoline engine\",\"Jet engine\",\"Steam engine\",\"Rocket engine\",\"Electric motor\",\"Rotary engine\",\"Turbine engine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "50143ed5-67b2-448a-b988-029cfbcf0acc",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical sewing machine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elias Howe",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Isaac Singer\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Eli Whitney\",\"James Watt\",\"James Hargreaves\",\"Richard Arkwright\",\"Samuel Crompton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f05a444-5041-465c-8153-6d051c0f84e9",
    "question": "What writing tool was invented by John J. Loud?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ballpoint pen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Fountain pen\",\"Pencil\",\"Felt-tip pen\",\"Typewriter\",\"Quill\",\"Marker\",\"Crayon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8faac377-aeb8-46f1-a8dc-8274c5c2a2cf",
    "question": "Who invented the first electric motor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Michael Faraday",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"James Watt\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "41396a74-2d68-400a-9339-eec6bb61ae69",
    "question": "What did Willis Carrier invent in 1902?",
    "correctAnswer": "Air conditioning",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Refrigerator\",\"Microwave oven\",\"Washing machine\",\"Electric fan\",\"Vacuum cleaner\",\"Dishwasher\",\"Electric heater\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "07bf13b4-87d6-472e-a7d9-154021f68dd0",
    "question": "Who discovered the structure of DNA?",
    "correctAnswer": "Watson and Crick",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Einstein and Bohr\",\"Darwin and Wallace\",\"Curie and Becquerel\",\"Mendel and Darwin\",\"Pasteur and Koch\",\"Salk and Sabin\",\"Pavlov and Skinner\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a1eba77-411a-4eed-a302-5f08aeaf91e6",
    "question": "Which scientist discovered radioactivity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Henri Becquerel",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marie Curie\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"Wilhelm Röntgen\",\"Pierre Curie\",\"Max Planck\",\"Niels Bohr\",\"Albert Einstein\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0be26ba-349b-44f6-b1f1-833a5507f037",
    "question": "What did Chester Carlson invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Photocopier",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Camera\",\"Scanner\",\"Printer\",\"Fax machine\",\"Calculator\",\"Telephone\",\"Radio\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8fbe4a4-0973-4a2e-b549-1d3ba8e13854",
    "question": "Who invented Velcro?",
    "correctAnswer": "George de Mestral",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"James Dyson\",\"Levi Strauss\",\"Earl Tupper\",\"Art Fry\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf2763a7-fbba-42be-8995-cc9e26bf7c05",
    "question": "Who invented the safety pin?",
    "correctAnswer": "Walter Hunt",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Eli Whitney\",\"Samuel Morse\",\"Elias Howe\",\"George Westinghouse\",\"John Deere\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "598bc744-8b68-4302-a43f-83726593ae37",
    "question": "Who discovered insulin?",
    "correctAnswer": "Frederick Banting",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Marie Curie\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Edward Jenner\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "18b9dcb9-da72-441c-977d-ecfde99347c5",
    "question": "What ancient navigation tool uses a magnetic needle?",
    "correctAnswer": "Compass",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Astrolabe\",\"Sextant\",\"Quadrant\",\"Globe\",\"Map\",\"Sundial\",\"Hourglass\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8798d468-543f-4de4-bcc4-c9661b747ce4",
    "question": "What did Alfred Nobel invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dynamite",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"TNT\",\"Gunpowder\",\"Nitroglycerin\",\"Nuclear bomb\",\"Plastic explosive\",\"Hand grenade\",\"Land mine\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ddd5b67b-2dad-4db3-938e-4f0d65aa551e",
    "question": "Who invented the Post-it Note?",
    "correctAnswer": "Art Fry",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Spencer Silver\",\"Richard Drew\",\"William McKnight\",\"Harry Coover\",\"Earl Tupper\",\"George de Mestral\",\"Charles Strite\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce611cb2-8902-4859-9b58-068ef5a22ff0",
    "question": "What did James Naismith invent in 1891?",
    "correctAnswer": "Basketball",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Baseball\",\"Football\",\"Soccer\",\"Tennis\",\"Golf\",\"Hockey\",\"Volleyball\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cfd942ac-aaa2-4432-b890-f30c7ed656b9",
    "question": "What did Bette Nesmith Graham invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Liquid Paper",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ballpoint pen\",\"Post-it Notes\",\"Scotch tape\",\"Highlighter\",\"Permanent marker\",\"Paper clip\",\"Stapler\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ce343e0-1fa7-4da9-add8-9ee77feae779",
    "question": "Who invented the zipper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Whitcomb Judson",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Levi Strauss\",\"Jacob Davis\",\"Elias Howe\",\"George de Mestral\",\"Walter Hunt\",\"Gideon Sundback\",\"Isaac Singer\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fefc360-396b-4ffd-aac7-ef588e61cd0e",
    "question": "Who invented bifocal eyeglasses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Benjamin Franklin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Leonardo da Vinci\",\"Galileo Galilei\",\"Johannes Kepler\",\"Anton van Leeuwenhoek\",\"Isaac Newton\",\"Louis Pasteur\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:41:25.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "60aee37f-4cb0-4669-a76d-182e7ae82795",
    "question": "Who developed alternating current electrical systems?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nikola Tesla",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"James Watt\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5303edad-38b8-424a-9e4b-bf8d13fb8a67",
    "question": "What year was the telephone patented?",
    "correctAnswer": "1876",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1860\",\"1890\",\"1901\",\"1855\",\"1870\",\"1885\",\"1910\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0acd78cf-bcf4-4d35-acc6-48f28354b563",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical typewriter?",
    "correctAnswer": "Christopher Latham Sholes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Babbage\",\"Remington\",\"Samuel Morse\",\"James Densmore\",\"Herman Hollerith\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Oliver Wendell Holmes\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7aa602e6-2e64-4b5f-b2ef-dd0359500f6b",
    "question": "Who discovered the principles of inheritance?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gregor Mendel",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Darwin\",\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Francis Crick\",\"James Watson\",\"Rosalind Franklin\",\"Robert Hooke\",\"Alexander Fleming\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2188c6e8-f47c-4a6d-8aaa-69f61ef87f98",
    "question": "What invention did Nicéphore Niépce create?",
    "correctAnswer": "First permanent photograph",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Telegraph\",\"Bicycle\",\"Sewing machine\",\"Camera obscura\",\"Motion picture\",\"Daguerreotype\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e681118-6266-494b-8d3b-4833e819fa0c",
    "question": "Who invented the first programmable computer?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles Babbage",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alan Turing\",\"Ada Lovelace\",\"John von Neumann\",\"Howard Aiken\",\"Bill Gates\",\"Steve Jobs\",\"Konrad Zuse\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b0c6376-c1b0-4071-a40b-46be0ceb94e8",
    "question": "What ancient civilization invented papyrus paper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Egyptians",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Babylonians\",\"Chinese\",\"Greeks\",\"Romans\",\"Mayans\",\"Incas\",\"Persians\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "353cbb1a-898a-4f86-8402-84b459362f31",
    "question": "Who invented Bakelite?",
    "correctAnswer": "Leo Baekeland",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Goodyear\",\"Wallace Carothers\",\"Alexander Parkes\",\"John Wesley Hyatt\",\"Edmund McIlhenny\",\"James Dewar\",\"Levi Strauss\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "65aa25bf-6186-4cef-b9b6-8b00f7dc827f",
    "question": "Who invented the first artificial heart?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robert Jarvik",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Christiaan Barnard\",\"Michael DeBakey\",\"Willem Kolff\",\"Charles Lindbergh\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Louis Pasteur\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "30a17b50-ce8c-4824-a83e-db8c7918a49e",
    "question": "What did Joseph Niepce and Louis Daguerre develop?",
    "correctAnswer": "Photography",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Telegraph\",\"Television\",\"Radio\",\"Microscope\",\"Telescope\",\"X-ray\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "926a742a-a317-469c-aeb8-1e292b521248",
    "question": "What navigation system did the US develop in the 1970s?",
    "correctAnswer": "GPS",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Radar\",\"Sonar\",\"LORAN\",\"Inertial navigation\",\"Radio direction finding\",\"Astrolabe\",\"Sextant\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "be45b25b-e39b-452f-8e91-c398eeef78e7",
    "question": "Who invented the mechanical reaper?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyrus McCormick",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John Deere\",\"Eli Whitney\",\"Jerome Case\",\"Charles Deering\",\"Obed Hussey\",\"Joseph Dart\",\"Benjamin Holt\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "911c392e-a9ec-449e-9281-34a02bd41888",
    "question": "What technology did Guglielmo Marconi demonstrate in 1901?",
    "correctAnswer": "Transatlantic radio transmission",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Telephone\",\"Television\",\"Telegraph\",\"Microwave\",\"Radar\",\"Electric light\",\"X-ray\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c76f94a-0f5d-4ea8-aedb-a83218cf0e8b",
    "question": "Who discovered the first antibiotic?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alexander Fleming",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Paul Ehrlich\",\"Gerhard Domagk\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "25e9a9f6-80c0-4cc9-b588-d7d1f2417a5e",
    "question": "What calculating device did Blaise Pascal invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pascaline",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Abacus\",\"Difference Engine\",\"Analytical Engine\",\"Slide rule\",\"Napier's bones\",\"ENIAC\",\"Calculator\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "da1a901d-78c3-40c5-8856-f08adf8a240e",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical helicopter?",
    "correctAnswer": "Igor Sikorsky",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Orville Wright\",\"Wilbur Wright\",\"Juan de la Cierva\",\"Frank Whittle\",\"Paul Cornu\",\"Louis Breguet\",\"Etienne Oehmichen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "863b397f-ca29-4495-85aa-5cc08903d349",
    "question": "What did Percy Spencer accidentally discover?",
    "correctAnswer": "Microwave cooking",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"X-rays\",\"Radioactivity\",\"Penicillin\",\"Plastic\",\"Vulcanized rubber\",\"Dynamite\",\"Teflon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "796bff0d-5e8c-4d90-8928-8872d5477355",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical diving suit?",
    "correctAnswer": "Augustus Siebe",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Jacques Cousteau\",\"William Beebe\",\"Charles William Davis\",\"John P. Holland\",\"David Bushnell\",\"Emile Gagnan\",\"Simon Lake\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d44d01c8-070e-4095-a086-d66ce89769e3",
    "question": "What did Karl Benz invent in 1885?",
    "correctAnswer": "Automobile",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bicycle\",\"Motorcycle\",\"Steamboat\",\"Diesel engine\",\"Airplane\",\"Train\",\"Helicopter\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3d8591d-160e-47c3-ab87-6496b0f2d1f7",
    "question": "Who invented pasteurization?",
    "correctAnswer": "Louis Pasteur",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Ignaz Semmelweis\",\"John Snow\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ceec62b-23e4-454d-9442-5db18e1a0e56",
    "question": "Who invented the safety elevator?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elisha Otis",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Henry Ford\",\"Charles Kettering\",\"George Westinghouse\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3c0fdc7-67f6-4b43-a791-ad59fc8d1d71",
    "question": "What was the first antibiotic discovered?",
    "correctAnswer": "Penicillin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Streptomycin\",\"Tetracycline\",\"Erythromycin\",\"Ampicillin\",\"Amoxicillin\",\"Chloramphenicol\",\"Sulfonamide\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "217fe545-0ac9-4390-a2a4-5cc09bb56d64",
    "question": "Who invented reinforced concrete?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joseph Monier",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Gustave Eiffel\",\"Isambard Kingdom Brunel\",\"John Smeaton\",\"Joseph Aspdin\",\"François Coignet\",\"William Aspdin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ae2d241-15e8-4154-a1b2-cbe99ae98c33",
    "question": "Who developed the first successful polio vaccine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jonas Salk",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Albert Sabin\",\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Maurice Hilleman\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9bdd5fe6-6c57-4924-8445-e4bae5cf3d42",
    "question": "What was the first mass-produced plastic called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bakelite",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nylon\",\"Polyethylene\",\"PVC\",\"Celluloid\",\"Polystyrene\",\"Teflon\",\"Kevlar\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3059fea-f4b7-4f9d-8bd3-68f64f181cfd",
    "question": "Who invented the first electric washing machine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alva Fisher",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"James Dyson\",\"William Blackstone\",\"Hamilton Smith\",\"Howard Colman\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "55c3a28b-213d-43f1-be1c-4c9f26048209",
    "question": "What was the first computer to defeat a chess champion?",
    "correctAnswer": "Deep Blue",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"AlphaGo\",\"Watson\",\"Deep Thought\",\"ENIAC\",\"Colossus\",\"HAL 9000\",\"WOPR\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5cf0042f-1887-4e2c-9683-e7856132612d",
    "question": "Who is credited with creating the World Wide Web?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tim Berners-Lee",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vint Cerf\",\"Bob Kahn\",\"Larry Page\",\"Steve Jobs\",\"Bill Gates\",\"Alan Turing\",\"John von Neumann\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d730aed6-866d-45fe-bc19-66f42b4dc4b8",
    "question": "What did Richard Trevithick develop in 1804?",
    "correctAnswer": "Steam locomotive",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Spinning jenny\",\"Power loom\",\"Steam engine\",\"Cotton gin\",\"Sewing machine\",\"Steamboat\",\"Telegraph\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5dc02fda-1333-471c-8fc4-537e025884a2",
    "question": "Who invented the first automatic dishwasher?",
    "correctAnswer": "Josephine Cochrane",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Margaret Knight\",\"Mary Anderson\",\"Hedy Lamarr\",\"Stephanie Kwolek\",\"Maria Telkes\",\"Beulah Louise Henry\",\"Ruth Handler\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8523f7c4-feb2-4219-8ecf-93878a89de80",
    "question": "Who discovered the principles of vaccination?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edward Jenner",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"Jonas Salk\",\"Albert Sabin\",\"Maurice Hilleman\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f8ffd64-7861-43d6-bc7f-ed47b3939ad9",
    "question": "What invention was patented by Charles Goodyear in 1844?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vulcanized rubber",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bicycle tire\",\"Automobile tire\",\"Balloon\",\"Rain boot\",\"Rubber band\",\"Rubber glove\",\"Rubber stamp\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f374faca-77b0-4431-988e-741d8f9d8d12",
    "question": "Who invented the Polaroid instant camera?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edwin Land",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George Eastman\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Louis Daguerre\",\"Ansel Adams\",\"Eadweard Muybridge\",\"Joseph Nicéphore Niépce\",\"Henri Cartier-Bresson\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec73f96e-e230-4a3a-881f-5d779fa487d9",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical induction motor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nikola Tesla",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Michael Faraday\",\"James Watt\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6554107-c3e2-4c27-8615-ccb050c7f41d",
    "question": "What invention led to the decline of whaling?",
    "correctAnswer": "Petroleum refining",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Electric light\",\"Natural gas\",\"Coal mining\",\"Synthetic oils\",\"Vegetable oils\",\"Nuclear power\",\"Hydroelectricity\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f5fbb25-4bcb-4b29-ad33-2aecab5a250c",
    "question": "Who created the first synthetic dye?",
    "correctAnswer": "William Henry Perkin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Dmitri Mendeleev\",\"August Kekulé\",\"Justus von Liebig\",\"Joseph Priestley\",\"Antoine Lavoisier\",\"John Dalton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f01d5fc-0f62-454d-8776-b09806002138",
    "question": "In what year was the first handheld calculator invented?",
    "correctAnswer": "1967",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1972\",\"1955\",\"1980\",\"1962\",\"1975\",\"1950\",\"1985\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7eadd08a-d0bc-4730-969a-0d4eed41c583",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical steam engine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Newcomen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Watt\",\"Richard Trevithick\",\"George Stephenson\",\"Thomas Savery\",\"Denis Papin\",\"Robert Fulton\",\"Oliver Evans\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "575860f7-10c8-49c7-95ea-78cef9cdf933",
    "question": "What material did John Dunlop use for the first pneumatic tire?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rubber garden hose",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vulcanized rubber\",\"Leather\",\"Canvas\",\"Cork\",\"Gutta-percha\",\"Whalebone\",\"Animal bladder\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3888e8d3-9507-4485-a5af-cc63afc45450",
    "question": "Who invented the modern toilet flush mechanism?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Crapper",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John Harington\",\"Alexander Cummings\",\"Joseph Bramah\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Henry Ford\",\"Albert Giblin\",\"George Jennings\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "343040ee-a72d-443c-b949-fb69f8f96c7e",
    "question": "Who discovered electromagnetic induction in 1831?",
    "correctAnswer": "Michael Faraday",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "949ffea5-1a48-4b9c-b4a5-4d2e3dbc9b88",
    "question": "What material did Charles Goodyear vulcanize?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rubber",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Plastic\",\"Glass\",\"Metal\",\"Wood\",\"Leather\",\"Paper\",\"Fabric\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed8b87e1-b1db-45d6-ad6f-4b157378994b",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical steamboat?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robert Fulton",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Watt\",\"Thomas Newcomen\",\"George Stephenson\",\"John Fitch\",\"Isaac Newton\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"Thomas Jefferson\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa8b0e06-09ec-4660-8d86-bb527fb3a456",
    "question": "In what year was the first Apple computer released?",
    "correctAnswer": "1976",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"1984\",\"1970\",\"1989\",\"1981\",\"1967\",\"1995\",\"1973\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc694d49-83ff-4f5c-8d7f-4d45186cee49",
    "question": "Who invented the mechanical clock?",
    "correctAnswer": "Yi Xing",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Su Song\",\"John Harrison\",\"Peter Henlein\",\"Christiaan Huygens\",\"Galileo Galilei\",\"Thomas Tompion\",\"Jost Bürgi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f7e853c-18d9-4b3f-a8be-ff9ef64265bc",
    "question": "What did Mary Anderson invent in 1903?",
    "correctAnswer": "Windshield wiper",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Dishwasher\",\"Washing machine\",\"Sewing machine\",\"Electric iron\",\"Refrigerator\",\"Vacuum cleaner\",\"Hair dryer\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "92b794a2-a803-4821-8285-de8f2cbcf475",
    "question": "Who invented Kevlar?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stephanie Kwolek",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Wallace Carothers\",\"Roy Plunkett\",\"Leo Baekeland\",\"Spencer Silver\",\"John Wesley Hyatt\",\"Charles Goodyear\",\"Edwin Binney\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ee754f4-eee0-4475-8ea3-a078a6447da2",
    "question": "What did Alessandro Volta invent in 1800?",
    "correctAnswer": "Electric battery",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Electric motor\",\"Generator\",\"Transformer\",\"Transistor\",\"Capacitor\",\"Resistor\",\"Voltmeter\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea50dd51-d952-4245-9783-20d29ce06bf4",
    "question": "Who invented the first solar cell?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles Fritts",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexandre Becquerel\",\"Albert Einstein\",\"Russell Ohl\",\"Bell Labs\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Michael Faraday\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a985dd6-eb8c-4693-9f24-08714c1b8f56",
    "question": "What did James Harrison invent in 1851?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mechanical refrigeration",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ice cream maker\",\"Air conditioning\",\"Freezer\",\"Ice machine\",\"Cold storage\",\"Refrigerated transport\",\"Domestic refrigerator\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ed7e47a-a9d6-45f2-916c-d1b41963d6ce",
    "question": "Who invented the pressure cooker?",
    "correctAnswer": "Denis Papin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Watt\",\"Thomas Newcomen\",\"Robert Boyle\",\"Thomas Savery\",\"Robert Fulton\",\"John Smeaton\",\"Nicolas Appert\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d70ab1eb-a8ef-4c4b-8a7c-16076cbe38d3",
    "question": "Who invented the concept of World Wide Web Consortium?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tim Berners-Lee",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Vint Cerf\",\"Robert Kahn\",\"Steve Jobs\",\"Bill Gates\",\"Larry Page\",\"Mark Zuckerberg\",\"Alan Turing\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "77c0caae-7c85-4761-827e-53ce1addbe7e",
    "question": "What was the first antibiotic discovered by Alexander Fleming?",
    "correctAnswer": "Penicillin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Streptomycin\",\"Tetracycline\",\"Erythromycin\",\"Ampicillin\",\"Cephalosporin\",\"Sulfonamide\",\"Chloramphenicol\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:45:51.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "efafdf5c-85d3-4600-8d7a-8ac722bbd837",
    "question": "Who invented the coherer, a radio wave detector?",
    "correctAnswer": "Édouard Branly",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Oliver Lodge\",\"Alexander Popov\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"Thomas Edison\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "080bef89-5187-4d06-9401-a20885f95428",
    "question": "What was the first message sent by Morse code in 1844?",
    "correctAnswer": "What hath God wrought",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"SOS\",\"Hello, world\",\"It works\",\"Come here Watson\",\"God save the Queen\",\"A test message\",\"Success\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5367f1ad-e273-4caf-bd02-07506038e44d",
    "question": "Who invented the cyclotron in 1932?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ernest Lawrence",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Enrico Fermi\",\"Niels Bohr\",\"Werner Heisenberg\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"J.J. Thomson\",\"Otto Hahn\",\"Leo Szilard\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "04bb34a1-9b56-4eab-bb77-43358d855e9e",
    "question": "What did Wallace Carothers invent in 1935?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nylon",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Rayon\",\"Polyester\",\"Teflon\",\"Kevlar\",\"Lycra\",\"Bakelite\",\"Polyethylene\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "66c7153b-c49f-4aaa-b619-53953bb75330",
    "question": "Who invented the resonant circuit for tuning radio?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nikola Tesla",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Edwin Armstrong\",\"Oliver Lodge\",\"John Fleming\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"Reginald Fessenden\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "1bddc592-8a48-40e1-afe9-b49ba66a936e",
    "question": "What ancient Greek invented the Archimedean screw?",
    "correctAnswer": "Archimedes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Aristotle\",\"Euclid\",\"Pythagoras\",\"Democritus\",\"Ptolemy\",\"Thales\",\"Hero\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6dda0c7a-0118-40e8-b1d7-95d953cbef24",
    "question": "Who invented Kodachrome film?",
    "correctAnswer": "Leopold Godowsky and Leopold Mannes",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George Eastman\",\"Edwin Land\",\"Louis Daguerre\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"William Fox Talbot\",\"Steven Sasson\",\"Joseph Nicéphore Niépce\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5dbb029d-55a7-49d2-bab9-d2093a1f6a96",
    "question": "What material did Leo Baekeland invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bakelite",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nylon\",\"Kevlar\",\"Teflon\",\"Celluloid\",\"Polyethylene\",\"PVC\",\"Rayon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "e429e2e0-eaf9-424f-b7f5-53d9b4895065",
    "question": "Who invented the first electronic digital computer?",
    "correctAnswer": "John Atanasoff and Clifford Berry",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alan Turing\",\"John von Neumann\",\"J. Presper Eckert\",\"John Mauchly\",\"Howard Aiken\",\"Konrad Zuse\",\"Charles Babbage\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba869386-08d1-4caf-8cb6-88dd3bae1939",
    "question": "What textile machine did James Hargreaves invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Spinning Jenny",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Power Loom\",\"Water Frame\",\"Spinning Mule\",\"Flying Shuttle\",\"Jacquard Loom\",\"Spinning Wheel\",\"Cotton Gin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6af0aaab-b568-4593-b498-616c14227d11",
    "question": "Who invented the antiseptic surgical technique?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joseph Lister",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Louis Pasteur\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Alexander Fleming\",\"Edward Jenner\",\"Joseph Lister\",\"John Snow\",\"Ignaz Semmelweis\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0825ad5-db02-4c35-9487-00ed6a477a79",
    "question": "Who discovered the thermionic emission principle?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Edison",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"John Ambrose Fleming\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"William Shockley\",\"John Bardeen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "177559b2-fc04-4b6b-835f-9befbea79e9d",
    "question": "Who discovered the Seebeck effect?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas Johann Seebeck",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"William Thomson\",\"Jean Peltier\",\"James Joule\",\"Georg Ohm\",\"André-Marie Ampère\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"Michael Faraday\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "aadeaef6-f2bd-4745-a7b6-4a073946c64a",
    "question": "Who invented the first digital electronic calculator?",
    "correctAnswer": "Al-Jazari",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Babbage\",\"Blaise Pascal\",\"Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz\",\"Wilhelm Schickard\",\"William Oughtred\",\"John Napier\",\"Herman Hollerith\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a287273-1171-483a-a983-f2fd1c1af74a",
    "question": "Which medical device did René Laennec invent?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stethoscope",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thermometer\",\"Blood pressure monitor\",\"X-ray machine\",\"MRI scanner\",\"Ultrasound\",\"Defibrillator\",\"Pacemaker\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a4a7da8-4b8c-4202-99e7-29afd2423868",
    "question": "Who discovered the principle of stereophonic sound?",
    "correctAnswer": "Alan Blumlein",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"Edwin Armstrong\",\"Emile Berliner\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Nikola Tesla\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "de319ade-06aa-488f-82ea-d9f5a6f635df",
    "question": "Who invented the Leyden jar?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pieter van Musschenbroek",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Luigi Galvani\",\"Alessandro Volta\",\"Benjamin Franklin\",\"Charles-Augustin de Coulomb\",\"William Gilbert\",\"Hans Christian Ørsted\",\"André-Marie Ampère\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f3e1179-0ac2-4726-93ad-3777f78210cf",
    "question": "Who invented the Fletcher-Munson curves?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harvey Fletcher and Wilden Munson",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"Edwin Armstrong\",\"John Logie Baird\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f77af9df-2996-415f-b814-febc23fbcffc",
    "question": "Who invented the steam turbine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles Parsons",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Watt\",\"Thomas Newcomen\",\"Richard Trevithick\",\"George Stephenson\",\"Thomas Savery\",\"Isambard Kingdom Brunel\",\"Robert Fulton\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "3503afa2-e8c9-481d-a15c-d0ee28374db5",
    "question": "Who invented the mechanical jacquard loom?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joseph Marie Jacquard",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"James Hargreaves\",\"Richard Arkwright\",\"Samuel Crompton\",\"Edmund Cartwright\",\"Eli Whitney\",\"John Kay\",\"Isaac Singer\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "c71b8cac-239a-4f70-bf57-c62ec86e7c0e",
    "question": "Who invented the audiometer?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harvey Fletcher",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"Edwin Armstrong\",\"Alan Blumlein\",\"Robert Koch\",\"Wilhelm Röntgen\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ba8a5f8-4a07-4751-bc4c-20ad9a774fb3",
    "question": "Who invented the fluid coupling?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hermann Föttinger",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Karl Benz\",\"Rudolf Diesel\",\"Nikolaus Otto\",\"Gottlieb Daimler\",\"Felix Wankel\",\"Ferdinand Porsche\",\"Wilhelm Maybach\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "edb6d91a-5c37-40ff-830f-c98aebb8fd83",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical hydraulic press?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joseph Bramah",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Blaise Pascal\",\"Archimedes\",\"Daniel Bernoulli\",\"Evangelista Torricelli\",\"Simon Stevin\",\"William Thomson\",\"James Watt\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6d5d715-5537-4a08-ae7f-8fdaa83203c7",
    "question": "Who discovered the Barkhausen effect?",
    "correctAnswer": "Heinrich Barkhausen",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Michael Faraday\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Wilhelm Röntgen\",\"Hans Christian Ørsted\",\"André-Marie Ampère\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "dad92d07-07e6-47c5-9cea-bdf6fe2773a0",
    "question": "Who invented the first ultracentrifuge?",
    "correctAnswer": "Theodor Svedberg",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Albert Einstein\",\"Linus Pauling\",\"Max Planck\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"Marie Curie\",\"Niels Bohr\",\"James Chadwick\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "38fdb831-3f32-4db2-bda0-8f3982b8ecd1",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical visible spectrum LED?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nick Holonyak",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Robert Hall\",\"James Biard\",\"H.J. Round\",\"Oleg Losev\",\"Shuji Nakamura\",\"Herbert Kroemer\",\"Zhores Alferov\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a7bb650-84b5-432d-a93a-db3aa88d3668",
    "question": "Who developed the first pneumatic tire for bicycles?",
    "correctAnswer": "John Boyd Dunlop",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Goodyear\",\"Robert William Thomson\",\"André Michelin\",\"Harvey Firestone\",\"Benjamin Franklin Goodrich\",\"Frank Seiberling\",\"Édouard Michelin\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7012b778-8431-47f3-b8de-fd2b1b081d7c",
    "question": "Who invented frequency modulation (FM) radio?",
    "correctAnswer": "Edwin Howard Armstrong",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"John Fleming\",\"Reginald Fessenden\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"Oliver Lodge\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e3a309a-0b5a-46ba-9717-f9ece3e62ead",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical vapor-compression refrigeration?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacob Perkins",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Carl von Linde\",\"William Cullen\",\"Oliver Evans\",\"James Harrison\",\"Alexander Twining\",\"Ferdinand Carré\",\"Charles Tellier\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d60d21d4-848e-428e-88cd-b3f0259bbb39",
    "question": "Who invented the cyclotron?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ernest Lawrence",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Niels Bohr\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"Enrico Fermi\",\"Werner Heisenberg\",\"J. Robert Oppenheimer\",\"Edward Teller\",\"Hans Bethe\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "90968eb9-0de9-40b7-9627-b2b1ec0de324",
    "question": "Who invented phase-contrast microscopy?",
    "correctAnswer": "Frits Zernike",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Ernst Ruska\",\"Max Knoll\",\"Zacharias Janssen\",\"Antoni van Leeuwenhoek\",\"Robert Hooke\",\"Ernst Abbe\",\"Carl Zeiss\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee59b5f8-4ca0-4940-a925-1c1c9d068cac",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical gas turbine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Frank Whittle",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hans von Ohain\",\"Alan Arnold Griffith\",\"Sanford Moss\",\"Aurel Stodola\",\"Aegidius Elling\",\"Charles Parsons\",\"Ernst Heinkel\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "8171a07c-e5b7-4a40-9c85-7cc04dcef405",
    "question": "Who invented the Audion vacuum tube?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lee De Forest",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John Ambrose Fleming\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Guglielmo Marconi\",\"Edwin Armstrong\",\"John Logie Baird\",\"Heinrich Hertz\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "12953e4d-5679-40ec-ab29-205359aaa5fe",
    "question": "Who invented the first electronic television?",
    "correctAnswer": "Philo Farnsworth",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John Logie Baird\",\"Vladimir Zworykin\",\"Charles Francis Jenkins\",\"Boris Rosing\",\"Alan Archibald Campbell-Swinton\",\"Paul Nipkow\",\"Kenjiro Takayanagi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "578a75fa-ebb3-494a-863f-488d58755766",
    "question": "Who invented the differential gear?",
    "correctAnswer": "Onésiphore Pecqueur",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Archimedes\",\"Leonardo da Vinci\",\"James Starley\",\"Karl Benz\",\"Richard Trevithick\",\"Ferdinand Verbiest\",\"Nicolas-Joseph Cugnot\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "63e26c2d-b54b-4901-bd4f-04ef8fa49c47",
    "question": "Who discovered piezoelectricity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacques and Pierre Curie",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Marie Curie\",\"Wilhelm Röntgen\",\"Henri Becquerel\",\"Ernest Rutherford\",\"Max Planck\",\"Niels Bohr\",\"Albert Einstein\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e68b0c3-2c57-40a0-8790-90e05b575eac",
    "question": "Who invented the first digital answering machine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Kazuo Hashimoto",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Thomas Edison\",\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Valdemar Poulsen\",\"Emile Berliner\",\"Almon Strowger\",\"Lee De Forest\",\"Claude Shannon\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6774b0fa-4307-443c-adeb-fd3dcdc3ac29",
    "question": "Who developed the first automatic exposure camera?",
    "correctAnswer": "Konishi Roku",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"George Eastman\",\"Edwin Land\",\"Oskar Barnack\",\"Steven Sasson\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Joseph Nicéphore Niépce\",\"Louis Daguerre\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "39abef79-2f74-486f-b905-364ca1e84182",
    "question": "Who invented the hydrofoil boat?",
    "correctAnswer": "Enrico Forlanini",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alexander Graham Bell\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Samuel Langley\",\"Glenn Curtiss\",\"Henri Fabre\",\"Howard Hughes\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ad108c7-2f81-4d11-9df7-0170cb7a688b",
    "question": "Who invented the first programmable electronic computer?",
    "correctAnswer": "Konrad Zuse",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Alan Turing\",\"John von Neumann\",\"Tommy Flowers\",\"John Mauchly\",\"J. Presper Eckert\",\"Howard Aiken\",\"Charles Babbage\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "b19a9fe8-2377-4ab3-ac4b-97a192cff4f4",
    "question": "Who invented the mechanical television?",
    "correctAnswer": "John Logie Baird",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Philo Farnsworth\",\"Vladimir Zworykin\",\"Charles Francis Jenkins\",\"Paul Nipkow\",\"Alan Archibald Campbell-Swinton\",\"Boris Rosing\",\"Kenjiro Takayanagi\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7d4698e-9856-4bb1-8e46-56933dd6f2b4",
    "question": "Who invented the first liquid-fueled rocket?",
    "correctAnswer": "Robert H. Goddard",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Hermann Oberth\",\"Konstantin Tsiolkovsky\",\"Wernher von Braun\",\"Sergei Korolev\",\"Hermann Noordung\",\"Robert Esnault-Pelterie\",\"Pedro Paulet\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6d6f06fe-35be-469b-b013-5946beffff49",
    "question": "Who invented the mechanical calculator Curta?",
    "correctAnswer": "Curt Herzstark",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Charles Babbage\",\"Blaise Pascal\",\"Gottfried Leibniz\",\"Wilhelm Schickard\",\"William Oughtred\",\"John Napier\",\"Herman Hollerith\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c4a5523-d39d-4f39-9c7d-2f30fe7dcd8e",
    "question": "Who invented the first electronic digital watch?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hamilton Watch Company",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Casio\",\"Seiko\",\"Pulsar\",\"Timex\",\"Bulova\",\"Rolex\",\"Omega\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "d898dd94-5f03-461b-9ce3-11c38a13448e",
    "question": "Who invented the first electronic digital stopwatch?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cronus Precision Products",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Seiko\",\"Casio\",\"Omega\",\"Longines\",\"Tag Heuer\",\"Timex\",\"Breitling\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "4dc65d95-16b3-4ad7-98b4-057c2eec609e",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical electric dynamo?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hippolyte Pixii",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Michael Faraday\",\"Nikola Tesla\",\"Thomas Edison\",\"Werner von Siemens\",\"James Clerk Maxwell\",\"Heinrich Hertz\",\"André-Marie Ampère\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "95e4f85f-3b12-421b-9bbc-419b0dccd5ae",
    "question": "Who invented the first practical hand-held electronic calculator?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jack Kilby and Jerry Merryman",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bill Hewlett\",\"David Packard\",\"Masaru Ibuka\",\"Akio Morita\",\"Tadao Kashio\",\"Edith Clarke\",\"John von Neumann\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb78339b-a89b-48a3-a54d-241bc4b9b370",
    "question": "Who invented the first electronic spreadsheet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dan Bricklin and Bob Frankston",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Bill Gates\",\"Steve Jobs\",\"Tim Berners-Lee\",\"Alan Kay\",\"Vint Cerf\",\"Ray Tomlinson\",\"Gary Kildall\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c0026db-b581-423c-931d-3704b72186de",
    "question": "Who invented the AK-47 assault rifle?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mikhail Kalashnikov",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"John Browning\",\"Richard Gatling\",\"Eugene Stoner\",\"Samuel Colt\",\"John Garand\",\"Hiram Maxim\",\"Georg Luger\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "509e32cd-8a8a-4e8f-8609-1a95bea91c1d",
    "question": "Who discovered the double-helix structure of DNA?",
    "correctAnswer": "Watson, Crick, Wilkins, and Franklin",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Linus Pauling\",\"Oswald Avery\",\"Alfred Hershey\",\"Martha Chase\",\"Friedrich Miescher\",\"Erwin Chargaff\",\"Phoebus Levene\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "41e63a2a-9470-485f-9b50-c5f86f10030c",
    "question": "Who invented the first transistor?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bardeen, Brattain, and Shockley",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Edison and Tesla\",\"Bohr and Einstein\",\"Faraday and Maxwell\",\"Fleming and De Forest\",\"Watson and Crick\",\"Curie and Rutherford\",\"Jobs and Wozniak\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "39dec1b6-0942-455b-a1b5-212c188c6a0d",
    "question": "What was the first commercial integrated circuit?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fairchild μL914",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Intel 4004\",\"Texas Instruments SN7400\",\"Motorola 6800\",\"Signetics NE555\",\"RCA CD4000\",\"National Semiconductor LM741\",\"Intel 8008\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f9e52f4-0146-4b24-9df3-d3ae2d73336a",
    "question": "Who invented the flip-flop circuit?",
    "correctAnswer": "William Eccles and F.W. Jordan",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Claude Shannon\",\"Alan Turing\",\"John von Neumann\",\"J. Presper Eckert\",\"John Mauchly\",\"Howard Aiken\",\"Konrad Zuse\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0057b51-ddc7-4525-bc97-0a8be736d15c",
    "question": "Who invented high-level programming languages?",
    "correctAnswer": "John Backus",
    "incorrectAnswers": "[\"Grace Hopper\",\"Alan Turing\",\"John von Neumann\",\"Claude Shannon\",\"Dennis Ritchie\",\"Bjarne Stroustrup\",\"Ada Lovelace\"]",
    "mainCategory": "History",
    "subcategory": "Inventions & Discoveries",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "createdAt": "2025-04-14T02:50:36.000Z"
  }
]